[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ थीम संगीत बज रहा है]
WOULD YOU MARRY ME?
क्या तुम मुझसे शादी करोगे?
ALL CHARACTERS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS, ETC. ARE FICTIONAL
सभी पात्र, स्थान, संगठन आदि काल्पनिक हैं
CHILD ACTORS WERE FILMED WITH GUARDIANS PRESENT
बाल कलाकारों को गार्जियन्स की उपस्थिति में फिल्माया गया
ANIMALS WERE FILMED UNDER EXPERT SUPERVISION AND WELFARE RULES
जानवरों का फिल्मांकन विशेषज्ञ पर्यवेक्षण और कल्याण नियमों के तहत किया गया
[Sejung's friend 1] It's someone from her work.
[सेजंग की दोस्त 1] यह उसके काम से कोई है।
Sorry for this.
इस के लिए क्षमा करें।
[♪ ethereal sparkle]
[♪ अलौकिक चमक]
[♪ dreamy, ambient music playing]
[♪ स्वप्निल, परिवेशीय संगीत बज रहा है]
[♪ upbeat pop music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक पॉप संगीत बज रहा है]
Mr. Kim?
श्री किम?
[gasps softly]
[धीरे से हांफता है]
[gasps]
[हांफते हुए]
Gosh, I'm sorry.
हे भगवान, मुझे खेद है।
[Sejung's friend 2] What's your problem?
[सेजंग का दोस्त 2] आपकी समस्या क्या है?
-Come on! -What's your deal?
-चलो! -तुम्हारा सौदा क्या है?
Guys!
दोस्तो!
[friends exclaiming excitedly]
[दोस्त उत्साह से चिल्लाते हैं]
Was it your team leader?
क्या यह आपका टीम लीडर था?
I couldn't tell from behind.
मैं पीछे से नहीं बता सका.
-Let me see. -Guys, stop it.
-मुझे देखने दो. -दोस्तों, इसे बंद करो.
Give the adults some alone time, will you?
क्या आप वयस्कों को कुछ समय अकेले में बिताने का मौका देंगे?
-I'm a grown-up, too. -Let's go!
-मैं भी बड़ा हो गया हूँ। -चलो चलें!
They've probably left by now, right?
वे शायद अब तक चले गए होंगे, है ना?
-[♪ whimsical music playing] -I suppose so.
-[♪ मनमौजी संगीत बज रहा है] -मुझे ऐसा लगता है।
You have lipstick on your...
आपके चेहरे पर लिपस्टिक लगी है...
No, the other side.
नहीं, दूसरी तरफ.
Just a second.
बस एक पल।
Right.
सही।
We should hurry out.
हमें जल्दी से बाहर निकलना चाहिए.
-Sure. -Right.
-ज़रूर. -ठीक है.
-After you.
-तुम्हारे बाद.
Just a second.
बस एक पल।
-Are they gone? Okay, let's go. -Yes.
-क्या वे चले गए? ठीक है, चलो। -हाँ।
Do you have a hammer?
क्या आपके पास हथौड़ा है?
Just a second.
बस एक पल।
A hammer?
एक हथौड़ा?
You don't have one?
आपके पास एक भी नहीं है?
No.
नहीं।
Oh, no.
अरे नहीं।
[♪ feel-good music playing]
[♪ अच्छा संगीत बज रहा है]
It should have everything you need.
इसमें आपकी जरूरत की हर चीज होनी चाहिए।
Right, thanks.
ठीक है, धन्यवाद.
How was your business trip?
आपकी व्यावसायिक यात्रा कैसी रही?
Oh, it went well. I just got back yesterday.
ओह, सब बढ़िया रहा। मैं कल ही वापस आया हूँ।
I heard you visited the house while I was away.
मैंने सुना है कि जब मैं बाहर था तब आप घर आये थे ।
None of our stuff was organized,
हमारा कोई भी सामान व्यवस्थित नहीं था,
so it might have looked like no one was living there.
इसलिए ऐसा लग रहा था कि वहां कोई नहीं रहता था।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
You must have some free time since it's the weekend.
चूँकि आज सप्ताहांत है, इसलिए आपके पास कुछ खाली समय अवश्य होगा ।
Oh, right.
अरे हां।
My husband is extremely busy.
मेरे पति बहुत व्यस्त हैं।
Even I can't get a hold of him on weekdays. [chuckles]
यहां तक ​​कि मैं भी सप्ताह के दिनों में उससे संपर्क नहीं कर पाता हूं । [हंसते हुए]
Sweetie, don't take on too much work.
प्रिय, ज्यादा काम मत लो।
It'll cost you your health.
इससे आपके स्वास्थ्य पर बुरा असर पड़ेगा।
I've been working out, so don't worry, sweetie.
मैं कसरत कर रहा हूं, इसलिए चिंता मत करो, प्रिये।
-Got it, sweetie. -Sure.
-समझ गया, प्रिये। -ज़रूर।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
Are you going to work out?
क्या आप कसरत करने जा रहे हैं?
I was planning to play some squash. Would you like to join me?
मैं स्क्वैश खेलने की योजना बना रहा था। क्या आप मेरे साथ खेलना चाहेंगे?
I'm afraid we already have plans.
मुझे डर है कि हमारे पास पहले से ही योजनाएँ हैं।
We had to call it off once before, so we can't do that again.
हमें पहले भी एक बार इसे रद्द करना पड़ा था, इसलिए हम ऐसा दोबारा नहीं कर सकते।
That's right. We already have plans.
यह सही है। हमारे पास पहले से ही योजनाएँ हैं।
-What a bummer. -[both chuckle softly]
-क्या बकवास है। -[दोनों धीरे से हंसते हैं]
[♪ whimsical music playing]
[♪ मनमौजी संगीत बज रहा है]
Sure, we can hang out next time.
ज़रूर, हम अगली बार घूम सकते हैं।
Got it.
समझ गया।
[closes gate]
[गेट बंद करता है]
-Is this really necessary? -[sighs]
-क्या यह सचमुच ज़रूरी है? -[आह भरते हुए]
Don't you know offense is the best defense?
क्या आप नहीं जानते कि आक्रमण ही सर्वोत्तम बचाव है?
He was clearly suspicious last time.
पिछली बार वह स्पष्ट रूप से संदिग्ध था।
With you gone... What are you doing?
तुम चले गए... तुम क्या कर रहे हो?
He's watching us.
वह हमें देख रहा है.
[♪ upbeat pop music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक पॉप संगीत बज रहा है]
He really is.
वह सचमुच है.
-Shall we? -Sure.
-क्या हम? -ज़रूर।
Is this absolutely necessary?
क्या यह बिल्कुल आवश्यक है?
[Kim Wooju] I thought offense was the best defense.
[किम वूजू] मैंने सोचा कि आक्रमण ही सबसे अच्छा बचाव है।
[Meri chuckles] True.
[मेरी हंसी] सच है।
Slow down, will you?
धीरे चलो, क्या तुम?
Walk faster.
तेज़ी से चलो।
My slipper's slipping off.
मेरी चप्पल फिसल रही है.
[Kim Wooju] That belongs in the trash.
[किम वूजू] यह कूड़े में जाना चाहिए।
[Meri] Now you're just being mean.
[मेरी] अब तुम बस मतलबी हो रहे हो।
These are my comfort slippers.
ये मेरी आरामदायक चप्पलें हैं।
Geez.
अरे!
Why is he still watching us? [giggles]
वह अभी भी हमें क्यों देख रहा है? [हंसी]
[Kim Wooju sighs]
[किम वूजू आह भरते हुए]
-Is he still looking? -Mmm-hmm.
-क्या वह अभी भी देख रहा है? -हम्म-हम्म।
[both chuckle]
[दोनों हंसते हैं]
My lips are trembling from all this smiling.
इस मुस्कुराहट से मेरे होंठ कांप रहे हैं ।
[sighs in relief]
[राहत की साँस लेते हुए]
WOULD YOU MARRY ME?
क्या तुम मुझसे शादी करोगे?
EPISODE 4
एपिसोड 4
[Ms. Oh] Right here,
[सुश्री ओह] यहीं,
you can see the sales from last year's holiday season.
आप पिछले वर्ष के छुट्टियों के मौसम की बिक्री देख सकते हैं ।
These were a huge hit because of the duty-free promotional deal.
ड्यूटी-फ्री प्रमोशनल डील के कारण ये बहुत बड़ी हिट रहीं ।
That's good to hear. I'll make a copy of this.
यह सुनकर अच्छा लगा। मैं इसकी एक कॉपी बनाऊँगा।
No, let me.
नहीं, मुझे करने दो.
I'm good, but thanks.
मैं ठीक हूं, लेकिन धन्यवाद.
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है]
I know it was him.
मैं जानता हूं कि यह वही था।
-What do you mean? -[gasps]
-क्या मतलब है तुम्हारा? -[हांफते हुए]
-Did that hurt? -[groans]
-क्या इससे दर्द हुआ? -[कराहते हुए]
What were you going on about?
आप किस बारे में बात कर रहे थे?
It definitely looked like him.
यह निश्चित रूप से उसके जैसा दिखता था।
I'm sure you saw someone similar.
मुझे यकीन है कि आपने भी ऐसा ही कोई व्यक्ति देखा होगा।
Why would Mr. Kim go there?
श्री किम वहां क्यों जाएंगे?
Enjoy. Here you go.
आनंद लें। लीजिए, लीजिए।
The company cafe serves great coffee with quality beans.
कंपनी का कैफे गुणवत्तायुक्त कॉफी परोसता है।
-Gosh, thanks. -Thank you.
-हे भगवान, धन्यवाद। -धन्यवाद।
What was that?
वह क्या था?
Where did you see Mr. Kim?
आपने श्री किम को कहां देखा?
Sejung saw Mr. Kim at a self-service photo studio.
सेजंग ने श्री किम को एक स्व-सेवा फोटो स्टूडियो में देखा ।
-[coughs] -[Sejung] Do you know the place
-[खांसते हुए] -[सेजंग] क्या तुम जगह जानते हो?
at the intersection that offers 50 percent off?
चौराहे पर 50 प्रतिशत छूट?
-I went there with my friends last weekend -[Meri coughs]
-मैं पिछले सप्ताहांत अपने दोस्तों के साथ वहाँ गया था -[मेरी खाँसी]
and saw someone who looked like Mr. Kim taking wedding photos.
और देखा कि मिस्टर किम जैसा दिखने वाला कोई व्यक्ति शादी की तस्वीरें ले रहा है।
Wedding photos?
विवाह की तस्वीरें?
[clears throat] You must've been mistaken. [chuckles nervously]
[गला साफ़ करता है] आप ग़लतफ़हमी में हैं। [घबराहट से हँसता है]
Exactly.
बिल्कुल।
Why would Mr. Kim go there?
श्री किम वहां क्यों जाएंगे?
He doesn't have a girlfriend.
उसकी कोई गर्लफ्रेंड नहीं है.
[Sejung] It seemed like a themed photo shoot,
[सेजंग] यह एक थीम आधारित फोटो शूट जैसा लग रहा था,
but the guy looked exactly like Mr. Kim from behind.
लेकिन वह आदमी पीछे से बिल्कुल मिस्टर किम जैसा दिखता था ।
-Tall with a petite head. -[Wonseok] A petite head.
-लंबा और छोटा सिर. -[वोनसियोक] छोटा सिर.
[Sejung] His hair had two parts.
[सेजंग] उसके बाल दो भागों में बंटे थे।
My hair also has two parts.
मेरे बाल भी दो भागों में बंटे हैं।
See?
देखना?
Go away!
दूर जाओ!
-Did you see the woman? -[Sejung] Sorry?
-क्या तुमने उस औरत को देखा? -[सेजंग] माफ़ करना?
If it was a wedding photo, there would've been a girl.
अगर यह शादी की तस्वीर होती तो इसमें एक लड़की होती।
-What did she look like? -[exclaims]
-वह कैसी दिखती थी? -[आश्चर्यचकित होकर]
[gulps]
[घूंट]
[Sejung hums thoughtfully]
[सेजंग सोच-विचार कर गुनगुनाता है]
[clicks tongue]
[जीभ चटकाता है]
[♪ upbeat dramatic music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है]
[exclaims softly]
[धीरे से चिल्लाता है]
She was a lot like you.
वह बहुत कुछ तुम्हारी तरह थी।
She had a figure similar to yours, Ms. Yoo.
उसका फिगर आपके जैसा ही था, सुश्री यू।
The height and everything.
ऊंचाई और सब कुछ.
She was just like you.
वह बिलकुल तुम्हारी तरह थी.
You should've seen her face.
तुम्हें उसका चेहरा देखना चाहिए था.
Her face? Well...
उसका चेहरा? खैर...
I couldn't because they were kissing.
मैं ऐसा नहीं कर सका क्योंकि वे चुंबन ले रहे थे।
-Were they kissing? -[Sejung] Yes.
-क्या वे चुंबन ले रहे थे? -[सेजंग] हाँ।
Their lips were locked.
उनके होंठ आपस में जुड़े हुए थे।
Why don't you check with the photo studio?
आप फोटो स्टूडियो से जांच क्यों नहीं करते?
Check who reserved that time slot.
जांचें कि उस समय स्लॉट को किसने आरक्षित किया है।
[Ms. Oh gasps] Ms. Shin, you genius!
[सुश्री ओह हांफती हैं] सुश्री शिन, आप तो प्रतिभाशाली हैं!
You're right. Why didn't I think of that?
तुम सही कह रहे हो। मैंने यह बात क्यों नहीं सोची?
I have the studio's number on my phone.
मेरे फोन पर स्टूडियो का नंबर है।
-[Wonseok] Give them a call. -Wait.
-[वोनसियोक] उन्हें फोन करो। -रुको।
-Here we go. -I don't think...
-यहाँ हम चलते हैं। -मुझे नहीं लगता...
I don't think they will share personal information.
मुझे नहीं लगता कि वे व्यक्तिगत जानकारी साझा करेंगे।
Hello, is this the self-service photo studio?
नमस्ते, क्या यह स्वयं सेवा फोटो स्टूडियो है?
I was hoping to ask you something.
मैं आपसे कुछ पूछना चाहता था।
Ms. Cha!
सुश्री चा!
I have something to ask.
मुझे कुछ पूछना है.
Shall we begin the meeting?
क्या हम बैठक शुरू करें?
-Ms. Yoo. -[Meri] I have something to say.
-सुश्री यू. -[मेरी] मुझे कुछ कहना है।
-I mean, ask... -[Sejung] What was that?
-मेरा मतलब है, पूछो... -[सेजंग] वह क्या था?
I can't quite hear you.
मैं आपकी बात ठीक से सुन नहीं पा रहा हूं।
[Ms. Oh] Ms. Yoo, can I have your attention?
[सुश्री ओह] सुश्री यू, क्या मैं आपका ध्यान आकर्षित कर सकती हूँ?
I had the reservation put under a different name just in case.
मैंने किसी भी स्थिति के लिए आरक्षण दूसरे नाम से करा लिया था।
Tosun, to be exact.
तोसुन, सटीक रूप से कहें तो।
[sighs in relief]
[राहत की साँस लेते हुए]
Couldn't you have told me that?
क्या आप मुझे यह नहीं बता सकते थे?
I was sweating in there.
मुझे वहाँ पसीना आ रहा था।
That's your fault for booking a studio close to the office.
कार्यालय के नजदीक स्टूडियो बुक करना आपकी गलती है ।
People could've seen us.
लोग हमें देख सकते थे.
I thought it would be safer near the office
मैंने सोचा कि कार्यालय के पास रहना अधिक सुरक्षित होगा
because it was the weekend.
क्योंकि यह सप्ताहांत था।
Anyway, I'm sorry. I'll be more careful.
खैर, मुझे माफ़ करना। मैं ज़्यादा सावधान रहूँगा।
-Has Mr. Baek reached out since that day? -No.
-क्या उस दिन के बाद से श्री बेक ने आपसे संपर्क किया है? -नहीं।
I'm going to cancel the home visit as soon as I can.
मैं यथाशीघ्र घर का दौरा रद्द करने जा रहा हूँ।
How?
कैसे?
[hums thoughtfully]
[सोचते हुए गुनगुनाता है]
We could be in a car accident, or a family member could die.
हम कार दुर्घटना का शिकार हो सकते हैं, या परिवार के किसी सदस्य की मृत्यु हो सकती है।
Wow, you lie like nobody's business.
वाह, आप तो ऐसे झूठ बोलते हैं जैसे किसी का कोई काम ही न हो।
Avoiding him should be a priority.
उससे बचना प्राथमिकता होनी चाहिए।
Things won't go well for you if I get caught.
अगर मैं पकड़ा गया तो तुम्हारे लिए चीजें ठीक नहीं होंगी ।
-Are you blackmailing me? -Of course not!
-क्या तुम मुझे ब्लैकमेल कर रहे हो? -बिल्कुल नहीं!
Is that how I came off?
क्या मैं इसी तरह से आया हूं?
It's just that I didn't want to put you out anymore.
बात बस इतनी है कि मैं तुम्हें और परेशान नहीं करना चाहता था।
The wedding photos we took together were more than enough.
हमने साथ मिलकर जो शादी की तस्वीरें लीं, वे काफी थीं।
Ah!
आह!
The wedding photos...
शादी की तस्वीरें...
You know,
आपको पता है,
I'm only saying this just in case.
मैं यह बात सिर्फ इसलिए कह रहा हूं।
I hope you don't read too much into it.
मुझे आशा है कि आप इसमें बहुत अधिक नहीं पढ़ेंगे।
A modeling gig.
एक मॉडलिंग का काम.
Just think of it as that.
बस इसे ऐसे ही समझिए।
[scoffs] I'm sorry to say this, but that's how I've always seen it.
[उपहास करते हुए] मुझे यह कहते हुए दुख हो रहा है, लेकिन मैंने हमेशा इसे इसी तरह देखा है।
You seem to be reading more into it than I am.
ऐसा लगता है कि आप मुझसे अधिक इस विषय पर पढ़ रहे हैं।
-Me? -It looked like
-मैं? -ऐसा लग रहा था
you were getting what you want by pretending it's for wedding photos.
आप यह दिखावा करके कि यह शादी की तस्वीरों के लिए है, जो आप चाहते थे, उसे प्राप्त कर रहे थे ।
You caught me off guard by swooping in like that.
तुमने इस तरह से झपट्टा मारकर मुझे चौंका दिया ।
-I swooped in? -[♪ upbeat dramatic music playing]
-मैं झपट्टा मारकर अंदर आया? -[♪ उत्साहवर्धक नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है]
Mr. Kim?
श्री किम?
[Sejung gasps]
[सेजंग हांफता है]
I was simply worried she'd catch us.
मुझे बस यही चिंता थी कि वह हमें पकड़ लेगी।
It definitely felt like I locked eyes with Sejung.
मुझे निश्चित रूप से ऐसा महसूस हुआ जैसे मैंने सेजंग से आंखें मिला ली हों।
Besides, the kiss?
इसके अलावा, चुंबन?
You started it.
आपने इसे शुरू कर दिया।
I never meant for things to go that far.
मैंने कभी नहीं सोचा था कि चीजें इतनी आगे तक जाएंगी।
All I wanted to do was to get us into a certain pose.
मैं बस इतना चाहता था कि हम एक निश्चित मुद्रा में आ जाएं।
But all of a sudden, you came at me like a bull...
लेकिन अचानक, तुम मुझ पर एक बैल की तरह टूट पड़े...
[scoffs] "Like a bull"?
[उपहास] "एक बैल की तरह"?
You've got to be kidding me.
तुम मुझसे मजाक कर रहे हो।
Just know that I wasn't trying to get anything from you.
बस इतना जान लो कि मैं तुमसे कुछ पाने की कोशिश नहीं कर रहा था।
What was that look just now?
अभी वह नजारा कैसा था?
Don't you believe me?
क्या तुम्हें मुझ पर विश्वास नहीं है?
[♪ dramatic sting]
[♪ नाटकीय स्टिंग]
[hesitates]
[संकोच करता है]
Whatever.
जो कुछ भी।
Here.
यहाँ।
I got you some clothes and shoes.
मैंने आपके लिए कुछ कपड़े और जूते लाए हैं।
I actually needed these. [gasps]
मुझे वास्तव में इनकी जरूरत थी। [हांफते हुए]
No way. Even your underwear?
बिल्कुल नहीं। यहाँ तक कि आपका अंडरवियर भी?
You're good with details, aren't you?
आप विवरण के मामले में अच्छे हैं, है न?
That's how you get work done.
इसी तरह आप काम पूरा कर लेते हैं।
Meticulously, without missing a detail.
सावधानीपूर्वक, बिना कोई विवरण छोड़े।
Consider me schooled.
मुझे शिक्षित समझो।
Return the favor with good work.
एहसान का बदला अच्छे काम से चुकाएँ।
The chairwoman liked the design proposal.
अध्यक्ष महोदया को डिजाइन प्रस्ताव पसंद आया।
She wants to hear from you in person.
वह आपसे व्यक्तिगत रूप से बात करना चाहती है।
Really?
वास्तव में?
Hold on a second.
थोड़ी देर रूकें।
If they like this new design,
अगर उन्हें यह नया डिज़ाइन पसंद आता है,
could they ask us to update the packaging for their current products?
क्या वे हमसे अपने मौजूदा उत्पादों की पैकेजिंग को अपडेट करने के लिए कह सकते हैं ?
Yes.
हाँ।
Think of the range of products Myungsoondang has.
म्यांगसूंडैंग के उत्पादों की श्रृंखला के बारे में सोचें ।
We'll tackle this project like it's do or die.
हम इस परियोजना को करो या मरो की स्थिति में पूरा करेंगे।
Don't pop the champagne too soon.
शैम्पेन को बहुत जल्दी न खोलें।
Myungsoondang's chairwoman is no joke.
म्यांगसून्दांग की अध्यक्ष कोई मज़ाक नहीं है।
How so?
ऐसा कैसे?
-Isn't she the founder's daughter-in-law? -She is.
-क्या वह संस्थापक की बहू नहीं है? -वह है।
She took the small steamed bun shop her mother-in-law ran at the market
उसने बाज़ार में अपनी सास द्वारा चलाई जाने वाली छोटी सी स्टीम्ड बन की दुकान ले ली
and turned it into the Myungsoondang we know today.
और इसे म्यांगसून्दांग में बदल दिया जिसे हम आज जानते हैं।
Despite being over 70,
70 से अधिक उम्र होने के बावजूद,
she visits the factory every morning and samples every product.
वह हर सुबह कारखाने का दौरा करती है और प्रत्येक उत्पाद का नमूना लेती है।
She also looks after the health and well-being of her bakers.
वह अपने बेकर्स के स्वास्थ्य और कल्याण का भी ध्यान रखती हैं।
That's admirable.
यह सराहनीय है.
-[exclaims quizzically] -I want the job even more now.
-[प्रश्नवाचक स्वर में कहता है] -अब मुझे नौकरी और भी अधिक चाहिए।
People like her tend to stay loyal, you know.
आप जानते हैं, उसके जैसे लोग वफादार बने रहते हैं।
They never change their view of you, either.
वे आपके बारे में अपना नजरिया कभी नहीं बदलते।
That's true.
यह सच है.
It's settled.
यह तय है।
I'm pulling all-nighters.
मैं पूरी रात जागता रहता हूँ।
I'll be ready with even Plans B and C.
मैं योजना बी और सी के साथ भी तैयार रहूंगा।
Did everything go smoothly at the funeral?
क्या अंतिम संस्कार में सब कुछ सुचारू रूप से चला?
Yes, the ceremony was simple because he had a small family.
हां, समारोह सरल था क्योंकि उनका परिवार छोटा था।
You did well.
आपने अच्छा किया।
I talked to Mr. Ko's wife this morning.
मैंने आज सुबह श्री को की पत्नी से बात की।
He was still quite young.
वह अभी भी काफी युवा था।
Assist the family in any way the company can.
कंपनी जिस भी तरह से संभव हो परिवार की सहायता करेगी ।
Maybe find a job for his wife in the company.
शायद वह अपनी पत्नी के लिए कंपनी में नौकरी ढूंढ़ ले ।
Of course. However, there's something I must report.
हाँ, हाँ। हालाँकि, एक बात है जो मुझे बतानी ही होगी।
It seems like Mr. Ko
ऐसा लगता है कि श्री को
was embezzling company money.
कंपनी के पैसे का गबन कर रहा था।
What are you talking about?
तुम किस बारे में बात कर रहे हो?
The internal audit team caught him the day before the accident.
आंतरिक लेखा परीक्षा टीम ने दुर्घटना से एक दिन पहले उसे पकड़ लिया।
When questioned,
जब उनसे पूछा गया,
he admitted to gambling.
उसने जुआ खेलना स्वीकार किया।
[♪ tense, melancholy music playing]
[♪ तनावपूर्ण, उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
He promised to pay the money back with his severance after retiring,
उन्होंने वादा किया कि वे रिटायरमेंट के बाद अपनी सेवानिवृत्ति राशि से यह पैसा वापस कर देंगे ।
but then the accident happened.
लेकिन तभी दुर्घटना घट गई।
Gambling?
जुआ?
[sighs] He wouldn't have.
[आह भरते हुए] वह ऐसा नहीं करता।
[sighs] I couldn't believe it, either,
[आह भरते हुए] मुझे भी यकीन नहीं हो रहा था,
but you never really know people.
लेकिन आप कभी भी लोगों को वास्तव में नहीं जान पाते।
[sighs softly]
[धीरे से आह भरता है]
He took a sizable amount, so what should we do?
उसने काफी बड़ी रकम ले ली, तो हमें क्या करना चाहिए?
If we file a police report, the press could get wind of it.
यदि हम पुलिस में रिपोर्ट दर्ज कराएंगे तो प्रेस को इसकी भनक लग सकती है।
What do you think we should do?
आप क्या सोचना है कि हमें क्या करना चाहिए?
It's wrong to speak ill of the dead, and he was a loyal employee,
मृतक के बारे में बुरा बोलना गलत है, और वह एक वफादार कर्मचारी था,
so I believe it'd be wise to keep this quiet.
इसलिए मेरा मानना ​​है कि इस बारे में चुप रहना ही बुद्धिमानी होगी।
[♪ ominous sting]
[♪ अशुभ डंक]
For now, Eungsoo will fill in for Mr. Ko.
फिलहाल, यूंगसू, श्री को की जगह लेंगे।
What?
क्या?
Me?
मुझे?
Accounting really isn't my strong suit.
लेखांकन वास्तव में मेरी मजबूत विषय नहीं है।
This will just be a temporary role until we hire someone.
जब तक हम किसी को नियुक्त नहीं करते, यह एक अस्थायी भूमिका होगी ।
I'll supervise the team myself, so don't worry.
मैं स्वयं टीम की देखरेख करूंगा, इसलिए चिंता न करें।
I'd feel better knowing you'll be taking charge.
मुझे यह जानकर अच्छा लगेगा कि आप कार्यभार संभालेंगे।
You could show Eungsoo how the work is done.
आप युंगसू को दिखा सकते हैं कि काम कैसे किया जाता है।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
I'll get back to my meal.
मैं अपना भोजन वापस लूंगा।
[sighs] Talk about a bomb going off.
[आह भरते हुए] बम फटने की बात करें।
Mr. Ko and his wife even had a meal here with us once.
श्री को और उनकी पत्नी ने एक बार हमारे साथ यहां भोजन भी किया था।
Right?
सही?
They were excited to win a vacation for his long service to the company.
वे कंपनी में उनकी लम्बी सेवा के लिए छुट्टी मिलने से उत्साहित थे ।
You should always drive carefully.
आपको हमेशा सावधानी से गाड़ी चलानी चाहिए।
He's lucky it was just him.
वह भाग्यशाली है कि यह केवल वह था।
What if his family were with him?
क्या होगा यदि उसका परिवार उसके साथ होता?
They'd all have been killed--
वे सब मारे गये होते--
Honey.
शहद।
What?
क्या?
[♪ poignant, melancholy music playing]
[♪ मार्मिक, उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
Come on.
चलो भी।
We all know the story, don't we?
हम सभी इस कहानी को जानते हैं, है न?
It shouldn't really be taboo in the family.
वास्तव में परिवार में इसे वर्जित नहीं माना जाना चाहिए ।
Wooju, I wasn't trying to upset you.
वूजू, मैं तुम्हें परेशान करने की कोशिश नहीं कर रहा था।
-I'm fine. -[acknowledges]
-मैं ठीक हूँ। -[स्वीकार करता है]
[clears throat]
[गला साफ़ करता है]
I'd like to excuse myself.
मैं अपने आप को माफ़ करना चाहता हूँ.
Didn't he like the food? [clears throat] He must be picky.
क्या उसे खाना पसंद नहीं आया? [गला साफ़ करता है] वह ज़रूर बहुत नखरेबाज़ होगा।
[loudly] You blabbermouth!
[ज़ोर से] तुम बकवास करने वाले!
Eat with a mask on.
मास्क लगाकर खाएं।
Then how would I be able to eat?
तो फिर मैं खाना कैसे खा पाऊंगा?
Just shut your mouth
बस अपना मुंह बंद करो
and stop talking nonsense at the dinner table.
और खाने की मेज पर बकवास करना बंद करो ।
You always pick on me.
तुम हमेशा मुझ पर ही तंज कसते हो.
Wooju said he was fine.
वूजू ने कहा कि वह ठीक है।
[Eungsoo] Mom, he isn't fine.
[युंगसू] माँ, वह ठीक नहीं है।
People rarely know this,
लोग शायद ही यह जानते हों,
but Wooju is more fainthearted than he seems
लेकिन वूजू जितना दिखता है उससे कहीं ज़्यादा डरपोक है
and gets scared easily.
और आसानी से डर जाता है.
[clears throat] When he was little,
[गला साफ़ करते हुए] जब वह छोटा था,
he stayed in his room and clutched his stuffed toy
वह अपने कमरे में रहा और अपने भरवां खिलौने को पकड़े रहा
whenever thunder struck. [chortles]
जब भी बिजली गिरी। [हँसी]
-His toy? -[Eungsoo] Yes.
-उसका खिलौना? -[युंगसू] हाँ।
I don't know where he found it,
मुझे नहीं पता कि उसे यह कहां मिला,
but it became his comfort toy.
लेकिन यह उसका आराम खिलौना बन गया।
[sighs in exasperation]
[चिढ़कर आह भरते हुए]
[♪ soft melancholy music playing]
[♪ धीमा उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[sighs softly]
[धीरे से आह भरता है]
[young Kim Wooju] Help.
[युवा किम वूजू] मदद करो.
Please help.
कृपया मदद करे।
Help...
मदद करना...
[tires screech]
[टायरों की चीख़]
[gasps, panting]
[हांफते हुए, हांफते हुए]
Are you okay?
तुम ठीक हो?
What on earth?
आखिर क्या?
[crying]
[रोते हुए]
-I was driving from that direction... -[young Kim Wooju] Dad!
-मैं उस दिशा से गाड़ी चला रहा था... -[युवा किम वूजू] पिताजी!
...when I saw him
...जब मैंने उन्हें देखा
-standing on the road looking like that. -Mom!
-सड़क पर ऐसे खड़े होकर देख रही हूँ। -माँ!
Dad!
पापा!
[taxi driver] Then I found the car and his parents thrown over there.
[टैक्सी ड्राइवर] फिर मैंने देखा कि कार और उसके माता-पिता वहाँ फेंके हुए थे।
[young Kim Wooju] Mom!
[युवा किम वूजू] माँ!
-[taxi driver] It's a miracle he survived. -[crying]
-[टैक्सी ड्राइवर] यह चमत्कार है कि वह बच गया। -[रोते हुए]
-[officer] On the road? -[taxi driver tsk-tsks sadly]
-[अधिकारी] सड़क पर? -[टैक्सी ड्राइवर उदास होकर tsk-tsk करता है]
You were driving your taxi down Route Three
आप अपनी टैक्सी रूट तीन पर चला रहे थे
when you saw the boy.
जब तुमने लड़के को देखा.
That's right.
यह सही है।
[♪ gentle, melancholy music playing]
[♪ कोमल, उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
Take it.
इसे लें।
My dad gave it to me as a birthday gift.
मेरे पिताजी ने इसे मुझे जन्मदिन के उपहार के रूप में दिया था।
[teddy] Enough with the tears, or the tiger will come and get you.
[टेडी] बहुत हो गया आँसू, वरना बाघ आएगा और तुम्हें ले जाएगा।
[♪ ethereal sparkle]
[♪ अलौकिक चमक]
Wooju!
वूजू!
Grandma!
दादी!
[crying] Grandma...
[रोते हुए] दादी...
Grandma...
दादी...
Are you all right?
तुम ठीक हो?
[taxi driver] Why are you crying, sweet pea?
[टैक्सी ड्राइवर] तुम क्यों रो रही हो, प्यारी मटर?
[young girl crying] Dad.
[युवती रोते हुए] पिताजी.
Did his mom and dad both die?
क्या उसके माता और पिता दोनों मर गये?
[taxi driver] Of course not.
[टैक्सी ड्राइवर] बिल्कुल नहीं।
They will be fine.
वे ठीक हो जायेंगे.
What if they both die?
अगर वे दोनों मर जाएं तो क्या होगा?
That poor boy!
वह बेचारा लड़का!
-[♪ melancholy music playing] -Come here.
-[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है] -इधर आओ।
Who will take care of him?
उसकी देखभाल कौन करेगा?
That poor boy!
वह बेचारा लड़का!
[young girl continues crying]
[युवती रोती रहती है]
[teddy] Enough with the tears, or the tiger will come and get you.
[टेडी] बहुत हो गया आँसू, वरना बाघ आएगा और तुम्हें ले जाएगा।
[♪ ethereal sparkle]
[♪ अलौकिक चमक]
Sorry for this.
इस के लिए क्षमा करें।
[♪ gripping whimsical music playing]
[♪ मनोरंजक सनकी संगीत बज रहा है]
Why are you still thinking about him?
तुम अब भी उसके बारे में क्यों सोच रहे हो?
It's not like the kiss was real.
ऐसा नहीं है कि वह चुंबन वास्तविक था।
All I wanted to do was to get us into a certain pose.
मैं बस इतना चाहता था कि हम एक निश्चित मुद्रा में आ जाएं।
But all of a sudden, you came at me like a bull...
लेकिन अचानक, तुम मुझ पर एक बैल की तरह टूट पड़े...
I didn't even use my tongue.
मैंने अपनी जीभ का भी उपयोग नहीं किया।
[Sejung] Mr. Kim?
[सेजंग] मिस्टर किम?
[gasps softly]
[धीरे से हांफता है]
[♪ ethereal sparkle]
[♪ अलौकिक चमक]
Or did I?
या मैंने?
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
I was like...
मैं जैसा था...
Have you lost it?
क्या आपने इसे खो दिया है?
Did I get too into character?
क्या मैं अपने किरदार में बहुत ज्यादा डूब गया?
No way.
बिलकुल नहीं।
There's no way.
कोई रास्ता नहीं है.
That's absurd.
यह बेतुका है.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक संगीत बज रहा है]
[whines]
[रोता है]
[exclaims]
[चिल्लाता है]
[Jingyeong] "A good place to confess your feelings."
[जिंगयेओंग] "अपनी भावनाओं को स्वीकार करने के लिए एक अच्छी जगह।"
A GOOD PLACE TO CONFESS YOUR FEELINGS
अपनी भावनाओं को व्यक्त करने के लिए एक अच्छी जगह
[Jingyeong over phone] Hey, Wooju.
[फोन पर जिंगयेओंग] अरे, वूजू।
What are you up to this evening?
आप इस शाम को क्या कर रहे हैं?
-[Kim Wooju] This evening? -Yes.
-[किम वूजू] आज शाम? -हाँ।
I get off work early today.
मैं आज काम से जल्दी छुट्टी पा लूँगा।
It'd be a crime to go straight home on a day like this.
ऐसे दिन सीधे घर जाना अपराध होगा ।
Don't you have other friends to hang out with?
क्या आपके पास घूमने के लिए कोई अन्य मित्र नहीं है?
Are you a loner at work?
क्या आप काम पर अकेले रहते हैं?
I was worried you'd be bored.
मुझे चिंता थी कि तुम बोर हो जाओगे।
So much for going someplace nice.
किसी अच्छी जगह जाने के लिए इतना ही काफी है।
Forget it.
रहने भी दो।
Okay, fine.
ठीक ठीक।
I have plans during the day, so I'll see you this evening.
आज दिन में मेरी योजनाएँ हैं, इसलिए मैं आज शाम को आपसे मिलूँगा।
Okay, call me when you're done.
ठीक है, जब तुम्हारा काम हो जाए तो मुझे फोन करना।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
Dr. Yoon, are you going on a date?
डॉ. यून, क्या आप डेट पर जा रहे हैं?
She definitely looks like she's going on one.
वह निश्चित रूप से ऐसा लग रहा है जैसे वह एक पर जा रही है।
What?
क्या?
Have you taken the VIP patient
क्या आपने वीआईपी मरीज़ को ले लिया है?
-Lee Sungwoo's blood pressure? -Yes.
-ली सुंगवू का रक्तचाप? -हाँ।
But I don't think it was necessary.
लेकिन मुझे नहीं लगता कि यह आवश्यक था।
He almost bit my head off for interrupting his sleep.
उसने अपनी नींद में खलल डालने के कारण मेरा सिर लगभग काट ही डाला था ।
That's one annoying little--
यह एक छोटी सी परेशान करने वाली बात है--
I feel bad for that guy.
मुझे उस आदमी के लिए बुरा लग रहा है.
He has to come whenever he's summoned, day or night.
उसे जब भी बुलाया जाए, चाहे दिन हो या रात, आना ही पड़ता है ।
[♪ upbeat pop music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक पॉप संगीत बज रहा है]
That should do it.
उसे क्या करना चाहिए।
Anyone would think that a newlywed couple lives here.
कोई भी सोचेगा कि यहां कोई नवविवाहित जोड़ा रहता है।
-Are you done changing? -[Kim Wooju] Yes.
-क्या आपने कपड़े बदल लिए हैं? -[किम वूजू] हाँ।
Is this really necessary?
क्या यह सचमुच आवश्यक है?
All newlyweds wear matching clothes.
सभी नवविवाहित जोड़े एक जैसे कपड़े पहनते हैं।
Are you cool or warm-toned?
क्या आप ठंडे या गर्म स्वर वाले हैं?
It looks good on you.
यह आप पर जंचता है।
Just a second.
बस एक पल।
I guess I don't look so bad.
मुझे लगता है मैं इतना बुरा नहीं दिखता।
[♪ whimsical music playing]
[♪ मनमौजी संगीत बज रहा है]
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
Here.
यहाँ।
Are you kidding me?
क्या तुम मजाक कर रहे हो?
If we're doing this, we might as well make it perfect.
यदि हम ऐसा कर रहे हैं, तो हम इसे पूर्णतः परिपूर्ण बना सकते हैं।
Did you have me come early so you could dress me up?
क्या आपने मुझे इसलिए जल्दी बुलाया था ताकि आप मुझे तैयार कर सकें?
There's still a lot of time.
अभी भी बहुत समय है.
That's only one of the reasons.
यह तो केवल एक कारण है।
We have things to get ready before people get here.
लोगों के यहां आने से पहले हमें कुछ चीजें तैयार करनी हैं ।
Pop quiz!
पॉप प्रश्नोत्तरी!
When's our wedding anniversary?
हमारी शादी की सालगिरह कब है?
January 6.
6 जनवरी.
You have a good memory.
आपकी याददाश्त अच्छी है।
That was barely a quiz.
वह तो महज एक प्रश्नोत्तरी थी।
Where was our honeymoon?
हमारा हनीमून कहाँ था?
Well? That's...
कि...
I never told you.
मैंने आपको कभी नहीं बताया।
-Geez, no wonder. -Here you go.
-हे भगवान, कोई आश्चर्य नहीं। -यह लीजिए।
I put together questions people could ask.
मैंने ऐसे प्रश्न संकलित किये जो लोग पूछ सकते थे।
Take a look.
नज़र रखना।
[inhales sharply]
[तेजी से साँस लेता है]
[exhales]
[साँस छोड़ता है]
2. HONEYMOON TRIP? LONDON, UK
2. हनीमून ट्रिप? लंदन, यूके
POTENTIAL QUESTIONS
संभावित प्रश्न
[Kim Wooju] London?
[किम वूजू] लंदन?
Did you plan to go to London for your honeymoon?
क्या आपने हनीमून के लिए लंदन जाने की योजना बनाई है ?
-Yes, to see Son Heungmin play. -I see.
-हाँ, सोन ह्युंगमिन को खेलते देखने के लिए। -मैं समझ गया।
Do you like soccer?
क्या आपको फुटबॉल पसंद है?
No, I just like Son Heungmin. I'm clueless about soccer.
नहीं, मुझे बस सोन ह्युंगमिन पसंद है। मुझे फुटबॉल के बारे में कुछ भी नहीं पता।
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
Man.
आदमी।
Your ex-fiancé was a generous man.
आपका पूर्व मंगेतर एक उदार आदमी था।
He was letting his girlfriend see another man during your honeymoon.
वह अपनी प्रेमिका को हनीमून के दौरान किसी अन्य पुरुष से मिलने दे रहा था।
[acknowledges]
[स्वीकार करता है]
I used 10 years' worth of my mileage to pay for our round-trip tickets.
मैंने अपनी आने-जाने की टिकट के भुगतान के लिए 10 वर्षों के माइलेज का उपयोग किया ।
That's why I got to choose the destination.
इसीलिए मुझे गंतव्य चुनना पड़ा।
Did you pay for the honeymoon as well?
क्या आपने हनीमून का खर्च भी उठाया?
You also paid for the apartment.
आपने अपार्टमेंट का भी भुगतान किया।
I paid his tuition twice, arranged his insurance,
मैंने उसकी ट्यूशन फीस दो बार चुकाई, उसका बीमा करवाया,
and paid for his TOEIC classes.
और उसकी TOEIC कक्षाओं का खर्च उठाया।
[gasps in awe]
[आश्चर्य से हांफता है]
It's fair since I was the first to earn money.
यह उचित है क्योंकि मैं पैसा कमाने वाला पहला व्यक्ति था।
He didn't have any money saved up.
उसके पास कोई पैसा जमा नहीं था।
Whoever has the money should pay.
जिसके पास पैसा है उसे भुगतान करना चाहिए।
Then, did he even thank you?
तो फिर, क्या उसने आपको धन्यवाद भी दिया?
[hesitates]
[संकोच करता है]
I guess he didn't.
मुझे लगता है उसने ऐसा नहीं किया।
How on earth did you two meet?
आखिर तुम दोनों की मुलाकात कैसे हुई?
While on vacation with my friends.
अपने दोस्तों के साथ छुट्टियों पर रहते हुए।
[♪ dramatic guitar music playing]
[♪ नाटकीय गिटार संगीत बजाना]
[friend 1] Meri!
[friend 1] Meri!
[friend 2] Yoo Meri!
[दोस्त 2] यू मेरी!
-Right here. -Over there.
-यहीं. -वहां.
-Hurry. -[friend 1] Oh, no.
-जल्दी करो। -[दोस्त 1] ओह, नहीं।
[friend 2] Meri!
[friend 2] Meri!
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
-[friend 1] Please. -[friend 2] Please open your eyes.
-[मित्र 1] कृपया। -[मित्र 2] कृपया अपनी आँखें खोलो।
[friend 1] Are you okay?
[मित्र 1] क्या आप ठीक हैं?
-[coughs] -[friend 1] Can you get up?
-[खांसता है] -[दोस्त 1] क्या तुम उठ सकते हो?
[friend 2] Meri, are you okay?
[दोस्त 2] मेरी, क्या तुम ठीक हो?
[Meri] I was drowning in the water,
[मेरी] मैं पानी में डूब रहा था,
and I woke up to a hottie looking down at me.
और जब मैं उठा तो देखा कि एक आकर्षक लड़की मेरी ओर देख रही थी।
You fell for his looks.
आप उसके रूप पर मोहित हो गए।
[chuckles] I guess.
[हंसते हुए] मुझे लगता है।
But no one decides to marry someone just for his looks.
लेकिन कोई भी किसी से सिर्फ उसके रूप-रंग को देखकर शादी करने का फैसला नहीं करता।
[paper rustles]
[कागज़ की सरसराहट]
Do you regret it?
आपको इसका पछतावा है?
Do I regret it?
क्या मुझे इसका अफसोस है?
I did.
मैने किया.
Why did I give him every piece of my heart?
मैंने उसे अपने दिल का हर टुकड़ा क्यों दे दिया ?
What a fool.
बेवकूफ।
That's what I thought love was.
मैं यही सोचता था कि प्यार क्या होता है।
I'm done with that now.
अब मैं उससे निपट चुका हूं।
Come on.
चलो भी।
Why do you need to change?
आपको बदलाव की आवश्यकता क्यों है?
I'm sure
मुझे यकीन है
you'll meet someone who won't take your love for granted.
आप किसी ऐसे व्यक्ति से मिलेंगे जो आपके प्यार को हल्के में नहीं लेगा।
[♪ soft piano music playing]
[♪ मधुर पियानो संगीत बज रहा है]
Will that day come?
क्या वह दिन आएगा?
Just so you know,
बस तुम इतना जानते हो,
that was very comforting.
यह बहुत आरामदायक था.
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
[phone vibrating]
[फ़ोन कंपन]
MOM
माँ
[automated voice] The call cannot be connected. Transferring to...
[स्वचालित आवाज़] कॉल कनेक्ट नहीं हो पा रही है। स्थानांतरित किया जा रहा है...
Could she be busy?
क्या वह व्यस्त हो सकती है?
-Seriously, Sunja? -Oh, it's hot.
-सच में, सुन्जा? -ओह, यह बहुत गर्म है।
Eat it all, why don't you?
सब खा लो, क्यों नहीं?
The person this food is for hasn't even eaten any yet.
जिस व्यक्ति के लिए यह भोजन है उसने अभी तक कुछ भी नहीं खाया है।
No need to be stingy when you made so much.
जब आपने इतना कुछ कमा लिया है तो कंजूस होने की कोई जरूरत नहीं है ।
By the way,
वैसे,
are Meri's future in-laws throwing a feast?
क्या मेरी के भावी ससुराल वाले कोई दावत दे रहे हैं?
Not really.
ज़रूरी नहीं।
I'm going to drop some off since I'm heading to Seoul
मैं कुछ सामान छोड़ कर जा रहा हूँ क्योंकि मैं सियोल जा रहा हूँ।
to visit my aunt in the hospital.
मैं अपनी चाची से मिलने अस्पताल गया था।
Oh, lucky them.
ओह, वे भाग्यशाली हैं।
If I had a son,
अगर मेरा एक बेटा होता,
I'd happily let him marry one of your daughters.
मैं ख़ुशी-ख़ुशी उसे आपकी किसी बेटी से शादी करने दूँगा।
That would mean enjoying all this tasty food every season.
इसका मतलब होगा हर मौसम में स्वादिष्ट भोजन का आनंद लेना।
[both chuckle]
[दोनों हंसते हैं]
Like I'd let my girls marry just anyone.
जैसे कि मैं अपनी लड़कियों को किसी से भी शादी करने की इजाजत दे सकता हूं।
Meri's fiancé's dad is a college professor.
मेरी के मंगेतर के पिता एक कॉलेज प्रोफेसर हैं।
So?
इसलिए?
That same educated family
वही शिक्षित परिवार
hasn't even said thank you for all the food you've given them.
आपने उन्हें जो खाना दिया है, उसके लिए उन्होंने आपको धन्यवाद भी नहीं कहा है ।
After you receive, you should give.
प्राप्त करने के बाद आपको देना चाहिए।
Talk about being rude.
असभ्य होने के बारे में बात करें.
I've been turning them down.
मैं उन्हें ठुकराता रहा हूं।
This is nothing to brag about.
इसमें गर्व करने की कोई बात नहीं है।
Anyone can tell they look down on you, except you.
कोई भी यह बता सकता है कि वे आपको नीची नज़र से देखते हैं, सिवाय आपके।
On top of that, your future son-in-law never even visited once.
इसके अलावा, आपके होने वाले दामाद ने एक बार भी आपसे मुलाकात नहीं की।
He's busy, that's why.
वह व्यस्त है, इसीलिए।
He doesn't lounge around all day.
वह सारा दिन इधर-उधर नहीं घूमता।
He works for a big investment company in Seoul.
वह सियोल में एक बड़ी निवेश कंपनी के लिए काम करता है ।
Like you know anything.
जैसे कि आप कुछ भी जानते हों।
I refused when they asked me to live with them in Seoul.
जब उन्होंने मुझे सियोल में उनके साथ रहने के लिए कहा तो मैंने मना कर दिया ।
Really?
वास्तव में?
That's right.
यह सही है।
He's been telling me to call him if I'm ever in Seoul.
वह मुझसे कह रहे हैं कि यदि मैं कभी सियोल में रहूं तो उन्हें फोन करूं।
You know what? I should ask him to get together tomorrow.
पता है क्या? मुझे उसे कल मिलने के लिए कहना चाहिए।
-Go ahead. -My son-in-law.
-आगे बढ़ो. -मेरे दामाद.
MY SON-IN-LAW
मेरा साला
[shower running]
[शॉवर चल रहा है]
[sighs in exasperation]
[चिढ़कर आह भरते हुए]
I thought it hit the lowest point, but there was worse to come.
मैंने सोचा कि यह सबसे निम्नतम बिंदु पर पहुंच गया है, लेकिन इससे भी बुरा होना बाकी था।
Why are only my shares dropping in price?
केवल मेरे शेयरों की कीमत क्यों गिर रही है?
When will you go up? Will you ever go up?
आप कब ऊपर जाओगे? क्या आप कभी ऊपर जाओगे?
MERI'S MOTHER
मेरी की माँ
[♪ ominous sting]
[♪ अशुभ डंक]
-Why is she calling me? -[phone vibrating]
-वह मुझे क्यों बुला रही है? -[फ़ोन वाइब्रेट हो रहा है]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है]
Meri told me to keep quiet for the time being.
मेरी ने मुझे कुछ समय के लिए चुप रहने को कहा ।
Does she know?
क्या वह जानती है?
Damn it.
धत तेरी कि।
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
[phone vibrates]
[फ़ोन कंपन करता है]
C: I'M IN ROOM 3613
सी: मैं कमरा 3613 में हूँ
"C"?
"सी"?
[shower stops]
[शावर रुक जाता है]
C: I'M IN ROOM 3613
सी: मैं कमरा 3613 में हूँ
[Jenny] Wooju.
[जेनी] वूजू.
Hit the shower.
स्नान करो।
I won't be long.
मैं ज्यादा देर नहीं रुकूंगा.
[giggles] Sure.
[हंसी] ज़रूर.
Yes, Ms. Yoo.
हाँ, सुश्री यू.
I'm afraid I'll have to cancel the home visit today.
मुझे डर है कि मुझे आज घर का दौरा रद्द करना पड़ेगा ।
Something urgent came up for my boss.
मेरे बॉस के लिए कुछ जरूरी काम आ गया।
I'm really sorry.
मैं वास्तव में माफी चाहता हूँ।
Please tell your husband how sorry I am.
कृपया अपने पति को बताएं कि मुझे कितना दुःख है।
Take care.
अपना ध्यान रखना।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[stutters]
[हकलाता है]
See? I was right!
देखा? मैं सही था!
Seriously, the guy's a lunatic.
सचमुच, वह आदमी पागल है।
He started punching me for just looking at him.
उसने मुझे सिर्फ इसलिए घूंसा मारना शुरू कर दिया क्योंकि मैंने उसे देखा था।
Oh, geez.
ओह, भगवान्.
I make my living with my face.
मैं अपने चेहरे से अपनी जीविका चलाता हूं।
How can this fly here? [exclaiming in pain]
यह यहाँ कैसे उड़ सकता है? [दर्द से चिल्लाते हुए]
[Sanghyeon] Are you Mr. Kim Gusik?
[सांघ्योन] क्या आप श्री किम गुसिक हैं?
Who are you?
आप कौन हैं?
I represent Mr. Lee Sungwoo.
मैं श्री ली सुंगवू का प्रतिनिधित्व करता हूं।
We should talk.
हमें बात करनी चाहिए.
MANAGING DIRECTOR BAEK SANGHYEON
प्रबंध निदेशक बेक सांघयेओन
You want me to say I assaulted him, too?
क्या आप चाहते हैं कि मैं यह कहूं कि मैंने भी उस पर हमला किया?
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
What a joke.
क्या मजाक।
Mister, there's video evidence.
श्रीमान, इसका वीडियो साक्ष्य है।
The security footage will be deleted,
सुरक्षा फुटेज हटा दी जाएगी,
but you'll find money in your bank account you never imagined having.
लेकिन आपको अपने बैंक खाते में वह पैसा मिलेगा जिसकी आपने कभी कल्पना भी नहीं की होगी।
As if.
मानो।
Would this be enough?
क्या यह पर्याप्त होगा?
300,000,000 WON
300,000,000 वोन
[♪ dramatic sting]
[♪ नाटकीय स्टिंग]
Why did he suddenly cancel? What for?
उसने अचानक रद्द क्यों कर दिया? किसलिए?
Beats me.
मुझे पता नहीं।
I don't mind avoiding the guy, but...
मुझे उस आदमी से बचने में कोई आपत्ति नहीं है, लेकिन...
You went through all this trouble for nothing.
तुमने ये सारी मुसीबतें व्यर्थ ही झेलीं ।
Oh, it's fine.
ओह, यह ठीक है.
Let me know when he reschedules.
जब वह कार्यक्रम पुनः निर्धारित करें तो मुझे बताइये।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
-I'll change out of this. -Sure.
-मैं इसे बदल दूँगा। -ज़रूर।
[clears throat]
[गला साफ़ करता है]
What's that?
वह क्या है?
[Meri] This?
[मेरी] यह?
It's the mascot I'll be showing at the presentation.
यह वह शुभंकर है जिसे मैं प्रस्तुति में दिखाऊंगा ।
-A mascot? -That's right.
-एक शुभंकर? -यह सही है।
I'm making one so I can promote the brand on your website and online stores.
मैं एक बना रहा हूं ताकि मैं आपकी वेबसाइट और ऑनलाइन स्टोर पर ब्रांड को बढ़ावा दे सकूं ।
-Would you like to see it? -Sure.
-क्या आप इसे देखना चाहेंगे? -ज़रूर।
Just a second.
बस एक पल।
I'll bring my laptop.
मैं अपना लैपटॉप लाऊंगा.
[character grunting]
[चरित्र घुरघुराहट]
It's not your money. Is that it?
यह आपका पैसा नहीं है। क्या यही बात है?
I can't even put it down as a business expense.
मैं इसे व्यावसायिक व्यय के रूप में भी नहीं रख सकता ।
[scoffs]
[उपहास करता है]
Are you and the victim trying to steal from me?
क्या आप और पीड़ित मुझसे चोरी करने की कोशिश कर रहे हैं?
I had to pay him a lot because there was a security footage.
मुझे उसे बहुत अधिक पैसे देने पड़े क्योंकि उसमें सुरक्षा फुटेज थी।
A security footage?
सुरक्षा फुटेज?
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
What about my father? What did he say?
मेरे पिताजी के बारे में क्या? उन्होंने क्या कहा?
As far as he knows, you're the victim.
जहां तक ​​वह जानता है, आप ही पीड़ित हैं।
To sell the story,
कहानी बेचने के लिए,
you should stay hospitalized for a few days.
आपको कुछ दिनों तक अस्पताल में भर्ती रहना चाहिए।
[sighs in exasperation]
[चिढ़कर आह भरते हुए]
I'm bored out of my mind.
मैं मन ही मन ऊब गया हूं।
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
Get me some sushi, will you?
क्या आप मेरे लिए कुछ सुशी लाएंगे?
I'm hungry, damn it!
मुझे भूख लगी है, लानत है!
[♪ tense pulsing music playing]
[♪ तनावपूर्ण स्पंदनशील संगीत बज रहा है]
[Meri] I went with a cute image that seemed to bring good luck.
[मेरी] मैंने एक सुंदर छवि चुनी जो सौभाग्य लाती प्रतीत होती थी।
Her name is Myungsoon.
उसका नाम म्यांगसून है।
I was thinking of adding her to the online purchase page.
मैं उसे ऑनलाइन खरीद पृष्ठ पर जोड़ने के बारे में सोच रहा था ।
I like it.
मुझे यह पसंद है।
[chuckles] Who's he?
[हंसते हुए] वह कौन है?
He's Myungsik.
He's Myungsik.
-Myungsoon's bestie. -[acknowledges]
-म्यांगसून की सबसे अच्छी दोस्त। -[स्वीकार करती है]
They look alike.
वे एक जैसे दिखते हैं.
No, he resembles someone else.
नहीं, वह किसी और जैसा दिखता है।
Who?
कौन?
My first love as a kid.
बचपन में मेरा पहला प्यार.
What? Was he that ugly?
क्या वह इतना बदसूरत था?
Did you say he was ugly?
क्या आपने कहा कि वह बदसूरत था?
He looks cute with those sparkling eyes.
वह अपनी चमकती आँखों के साथ बहुत प्यारा लग रहा है।
How can you think he's cute?
आप कैसे सोच सकते हैं कि वह प्यारा है?
He looks like a pompous little troublemaker.
वह एक घमंडी छोटा उपद्रवी व्यक्ति लगता है ।
That's part of his charm.
यह उनके आकर्षण का हिस्सा है।
Are you still in touch with Myungsik?
क्या आप अभी भी म्युनगसिक के संपर्क में हैं?
My first love?
मेरा पहला प्यार?
Of course not.
बिल्कुल नहीं।
That was a long time ago.
बहुत समय पहले की बात है।
Do you also remember your first love?
क्या आपको भी अपना पहला प्यार याद है?
[inhales sharply] I'm not sure. [exhales]
[तेज़ी से साँस लेता है] मुझे यकीन नहीं है। [साँस छोड़ता है]
I haven't experienced love yet.
मैंने अभी तक प्रेम का अनुभव नहीं किया है।
You liar.
झूठे कहीं के।
[♪ whimsical music playing]
[♪ मनमौजी संगीत बज रहा है]
I'm sorry.
मुझे माफ़ करें।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
What was that?
वह क्या था?
I threw it a bit too hard, didn't I?
मैंने इसे थोड़ा ज्यादा जोर से फेंका, है ना?
-[chuckling] I mean... -[phone vibrating]
-[हँसते हुए] मेरा मतलब है... -[फ़ोन हिल रहा है]
-Sorry about that. -Hold on.
-इसके लिए क्षमा करें। -रुको।
[line ringing]
[लाइन रिंगिंग]
Hey, Wooju. Where are you?
अरे, वूजू, तुम कहाँ हो?
Oh, of course.
हां, बिल्कुल।
When did we agree to meet again?
हम दोबारा मिलने के लिए कब सहमत हुए?
Aren't you on your way over?
क्या आप रास्ते में नहीं हैं?
I'm not.
मैं नहीं हूँ।
I'll head out right now.
मैं अभी निकलूंगा.
Right.
सही।
Actually, it's fine.
वास्तव में, यह ठीक है।
What can you do when you're busy?
जब आप व्यस्त हों तो आप क्या कर सकते हैं?
Actually, my senior asked me to cover an on-call shift,
दरअसल, मेरे सीनियर ने मुझे एक ऑन-कॉल शिफ्ट कवर करने के लिए कहा था,
so I'm calling to cancel.
इसलिए मैं रद्द करने के लिए फोन कर रहा हूँ.
I'm the one who's sorry.
मैं ही वह व्यक्ति हूं जिसे खेद है।
I'll make it up to you with a meal.
मैं भोजन कराकर तुम्हारी भरपाई कर दूंगा।
Sure, I'm being called right now.
हाँ, मुझे अभी बुलाया जा रहा है।
Bye. Sure thing.
अलविदा। ज़रूर।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[sighs sheepishly]
[शर्मिंदगी से आह भरते हुए]
Maybe I should've said I'd wait.
शायद मुझे कहना चाहिए था कि मैं इंतजार करूंगा।
[♪ gentle pop music playing over speakers]
[♪ स्पीकर पर बज रहा हल्का पॉप संगीत]
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
Welcome.
स्वागत।
I'll have your strongest drink.
मैं तुम्हारा सबसे तेज़ पेय लूँगा।
Got it.
समझ गया।
[sighs softly]
[धीरे से आह भरता है]
Seriously.
गंभीरता से।
Why did I pretend I was busy?
मैंने ऐसा दिखावा क्यों किया कि मैं व्यस्त हूं?
[groans softly]
[धीरे से कराहता है]
Damn.
लानत है।
[exclaims] You're such a loser.
[चिल्लाता है] तुम बहुत असफल हो।
[exclaims quizzically]
[आश्चर्यजनक ढंग से कहता है]
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[♪ melancholy music fades]
[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत धीमा पड़ जाता है]
[♪ soft jazz music playing over speakers]
[♪ स्पीकर पर धीमा जैज़ संगीत बज रहा है]
[exhales sharply]
[तेजी से साँस छोड़ता है]
[exclaims]
[चिल्लाता है]
[breathes heavily]
[भारी साँस लेता है]
[clears throat]
[गला साफ़ करता है]
Making a living is no joke.
जीविका कमाना कोई मज़ाक नहीं है।
Being an employee is tough.
कर्मचारी होना कठिन है.
But all we can do is tough it out.
लेकिन हम बस इतना ही कर सकते हैं कि इसे कठिन बना दें।
That VIP patient you work for.
वह वीआईपी मरीज जिसके लिए आप काम करते हैं।
Rumor has already spread about what an ass he is.
उसके बारे में पहले ही अफवाह फैल चुकी है कि वह कितना मूर्ख है।
He's faking an injury just to stay hospitalized.
वह अस्पताल में भर्ती रहने के लिए चोट का नाटक कर रहा है ।
Still, you handled him gracefully.
फिर भी, आपने उसे शालीनता से संभाला।
I have mad respect.
मैं उनके प्रति बहुत सम्मान रखता हूं।
Do I know you?
क्या मैं आपको जानता हूं?
It's me.
यह मैं हूं।
We ran into each other earlier at the hospital.
हम पहले भी अस्पताल में एक दूसरे से मिले थे।
I'm the doctor.
मैं डॉक्टर हूं.
-Who's been saying those things? -What?
-ये बातें कौन कह रहा है? -क्या?
They should be fired.
उन्हें नौकरी से निकाल देना चाहिए.
The huge donation to the cancer center was made in return for silence.
कैंसर केंद्र को यह विशाल दान मौन रहने के बदले में दिया गया।
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
You got it all wrong.
आपने सब कुछ ग़लत समझा है।
I only brought it up to comfort you,
मैंने तो बस तुम्हें दिलासा देने के लिए यह बात कही थी,
as I'm just an employee myself.
क्योंकि मैं स्वयं एक कर्मचारी हूं।
Unsolicited words of comfort are just arrogance.
सांत्वना के अनचाहे शब्द केवल अहंकार हैं।
I apologize.
मैं क्षमाप्रार्थी हूं।
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
Why twist what I meant when I was trying to be nice?
जब मैं अच्छा बनने की कोशिश कर रहा था तो मेरी बात को तोड़-मरोड़ कर क्यों कहा गया ?
It's not like I talked badly about anyone.
ऐसा नहीं है कि मैंने किसी के बारे में बुरी बात कही हो।
[exclaims in realization]
[अहसास में चिल्लाता है]
Are you telling me to shut up since you spent the money?
क्या आप मुझे चुप रहने को कह रहे हैं, क्योंकि आपने पैसे खर्च कर दिए हैं?
You seem to think money solves everything,
आपको लगता है कि पैसा ही सब कुछ हल कर देता है,
but there's more to it than that.
लेकिन इसमें इससे भी अधिक बात है।
It's simpler this way.
इस तरह से यह अधिक सरल है।
Work only as much as you're paid
केवल उतना ही काम करें जितना आपको भुगतान किया जाता है
and stay just as quiet.
और वैसे ही शांत रहो।
[inhales deeply]
[गहरी साँस लेता है]
That way, no one will be drained for no reason.
इस तरह, किसी को भी बिना किसी कारण के थकावट नहीं होगी ।
How can people live without draining themselves emotionally?
लोग भावनात्मक रूप से खुद को थकाये बिना कैसे रह सकते हैं?
If you're upset,
यदि आप परेशान हैं,
open up and let others comfort you instead of acting tough.
कठोर व्यवहार करने के बजाय, खुलकर बात करें और दूसरों को आपको सांत्वना देने दें ।
Why would you be drinking here if you weren't upset?
अगर आप परेशान नहीं होते तो यहां शराब क्यों पीते ?
Who drinks alone like this when they're not upset,
जब वो परेशान नहीं होता तो ऐसे अकेले कौन पीता है ,
like I am?
जैसे मैं हूँ?
[♪ upbeat whimsical music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक सनकी संगीत बज रहा है]
[stutters] What is it?
[हकलाते हुए] यह क्या है?
What?
क्या?
What is it?
यह क्या है?
Do you think I'm drowning my sorrows because a guy stood me up?
क्या आपको लगता है कि मैं अपने दुखों को इसलिए भुला रही हूं क्योंकि एक आदमी ने मुझे छोड़ दिया?
I'm not.
मैं नहीं हूँ।
Excuse me, can I get a refill?
क्षमा करें, क्या मुझे पुनःभरण मिल सकता है?
[bartender] Sure thing.
[बारटेंडर] ज़रूर।
[♪ upbeat jazz music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक जैज़ संगीत बज रहा है]
Are you trying to flirt with me?
क्या तुम मेरे साथ फ़्लर्ट करने की कोशिश कर रहे हो?
I'm telling you to drink up and go.
मैं तुमसे कह रहा हूं कि पी लो और चले जाओ।
I'd rather drink in peace.
मैं शांति से पीना पसंद करूंगा।
[Jingyeong sighs]
[जिंगयेओंग आह भरता है]
Here you go.
हेयर यू गो।
[satisfied exhale]
[संतुष्ट साँस छोड़ना]
FROM YEOSU TO GANGNAM
येओसु से गंगनम तक
[automated voice] Ladies and gentlemen,
[स्वचालित आवाज] देवियो और सज्जनो,
we will soon arrive in Gangnam, our destination.
हम जल्द ही अपने गंतव्य गंगनम पहुंच जायेंगे ।
Please check if you have left any luggage behind.
कृपया जांच लें कि क्या आपने कोई सामान पीछे छोड़ दिया है।
[grunts, panting]
[घुरघुराहट, हाँफना]
[Kim Wooju] With this renewal,
[किम वूजू] इस नवीनीकरण के साथ,
we hope to strengthen our brand identity across all customer demographics.
हम सभी ग्राहक जनसांख्यिकी में अपनी ब्रांड पहचान को मजबूत करने की आशा करते हैं ।
PACKAGE RENEWAL STATUS UPDATE
पैकेज नवीनीकरण स्थिति अद्यतन
The new packaging design will be used on small gift packages,
नए पैकेजिंग डिजाइन का उपयोग छोटे उपहार पैकेजों पर किया जाएगा,
our website's purchase pages, and gift features on social media.
हमारी वेबसाइट के खरीद पृष्ठों, और सोशल मीडिया पर उपहार सुविधाओं।
We hope the new mascot in the design will help attract a younger customer base.
हमें उम्मीद है कि डिजाइन में नया शुभंकर युवा ग्राहकों को आकर्षित करने में मदद करेगा।
There are ads on social media,
सोशल मीडिया पर विज्ञापन हैं,
plus vouchers and coupons, but...
प्लस वाउचर और कूपन, लेकिन...
[Mom] I'm in Seoul.
[माँ] मैं सियोल में हूँ।
I made some side dishes, so I'll drop by your in-laws' place.
मैंने कुछ साइड डिशेज बनाई हैं, इसलिए मैं आपके ससुराल में भी जाऊंगी।
[Meri] My in-laws?
[मेरी] मेरे ससुराल वाले?
[Kim Wooju] ...we look forward to greater brand familiarity
[किम वूजू] ...हम ब्रांड की अधिक पहचान की आशा करते हैं
and increased attention on...
और इस पर अधिक ध्यान दिया गया...
[♪ gripping whimsical music playing]
[♪ मनोरंजक सनकी संगीत बज रहा है]
...on online platforms.
...ऑनलाइन प्लेटफॉर्म पर।
Let's dive in.
आइये इसमें गोता लगाएँ।
2025 MYUNGSOONDANG LEADERSHIP ESSENTIAL ACADEMY
2025 म्यांगसूंडांग लीडरशिप एसेंशियल अकादमी
Why aren't you picking up?
आप क्यों नहीं उठा रहे हैं?
MOM
माँ
Goodness me. Hello.
हे भगवान! नमस्ते!
[exhales]
[साँस छोड़ता है]
Oh dear, I can't have this spilling.
हे भगवान, मैं इसे गिरने नहीं दे सकता।
MERI
उपाय
[automated voice] The call cannot be connected. Transferring to...
[स्वचालित आवाज़] कॉल कनेक्ट नहीं हो पा रही है। स्थानांतरित किया जा रहा है...
[line ringing]
[लाइन रिंगिंग]
Is something up?
क्या कुछ हुआ है?
You're up soon.
आप जल्द ही उठेंगे.
My mom's in Seoul and heading to Wooju's.
मेरी माँ सियोल में हैं और वूजू की ओर जा रही हैं।
[exclaims in realization]
[अहसास में चिल्लाता है]
She doesn't know yet, does she?
उसे अभी तक पता नहीं है, है ना?
[hums thoughtfully]
[सोचते हुए गुनगुनाता है]
Ms. Yoo, you're up next.
सुश्री यू, अब आपका नंबर है।
I'll be right there.
मैं अभी वहाँ रहुंगा।
Then, text me Mr. Kim's address.
फिर, मुझे श्री किम का पता भेजिए।
I'll go there and try to stop your mom.
मैं वहां जाऊंगा और तुम्हारी माँ को रोकने की कोशिश करूंगा।
You give the presentation.
आप प्रस्तुति दीजिए.
-Don't worry. -But...
-चिंता मत करो. -लेकिन...
Go on.
जारी रखें।
Thank you so much for doing me this huge favor.
मुझ पर इतना बड़ा उपकार करने के लिए आपका बहुत-बहुत धन्यवाद ।
[hums thoughtfully]
[सोचते हुए गुनगुनाता है]
The wedding is off?
शादी रद्द हो गई?
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
What a joke of a family.
यह कैसा मज़ाक है परिवार का!
Don't you and your daughter talk?
क्या आप और आपकी बेटी बात नहीं करते?
It was called off ages ago.
इसे बहुत पहले ही बंद कर दिया गया था।
Wait.
इंतज़ार।
[chuckles nervously] What do you mean it was called off?
[घबराहट से हंसते हुए] आपका क्या मतलब है कि इसे रद्द कर दिया गया?
This is news to me.
यह मेरे लिए समाचार है।
If you have any questions, talk to your daughter.
यदि आपके कोई प्रश्न हों तो अपनी बेटी से बात करें।
We've got nothing more to say.
हमारे पास कहने को और कुछ नहीं है।
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
Ms. Chun, don't be like this.
सुश्री चुन, ऐसा मत करो।
They probably argued a little,
उन्होंने शायद थोड़ी बहस की होगी,
but that's common for couples before getting married.
लेकिन शादी से पहले जोड़ों के लिए यह आम बात है ।
If Meri did something wrong, I'll set her straight.
अगर मेरी ने कुछ ग़लत किया है तो मैं उसे सही कर दूँगा।
A wedding isn't something to play around with.
शादी कोई खिलवाड़ करने वाली चीज़ नहीं है।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
Ms. Chun, why don't you cool off and take this?
सुश्री चुन, आप शांत क्यों नहीं हो जातीं और इसे स्वीकार क्यों नहीं कर लेतीं?
I made you some of the side dishes you love.
मैंने आपके लिए कुछ पसंदीदा व्यंजन बनाए हैं।
There's green onion kimchi.
वहाँ हरी प्याज किमची है।
Here.
यहाँ।
[hesitates]
[संकोच करता है]
You shouldn't have.
तुम्हें ऐसा नहीं करना चाहिए था.
Seriously?
गंभीरता से?
It'd be rude to turn this down.
इसे अस्वीकार करना अशिष्टता होगी।
[♪ gripping dramatic music playing]
[♪ मनोरंजक नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है]
[GPS] You're almost at your destination.
[जीपीएस] आप लगभग अपने गंतव्य पर पहुंच चुके हैं।
Look here, Ms. Oh.
इधर देखिए, सुश्री ओह।
I say this because I feel bad for you.
मैं यह इसलिए कह रहा हूं क्योंकि मुझे आपके लिए बुरा लग रहा है।
This isn't a lovers' spat.
यह प्रेमियों का झगड़ा नहीं है।
It's over between them.
उनके बीच मामला ख़त्म हो गया है।
You know how your daughter is.
आप जानते हैं कि आपकी बेटी कैसी है।
She's vicious and nasty.
वह क्रूर और दुष्ट है।
No guy would be able to handle her.
कोई भी आदमी उसे संभाल नहीं पाएगा.
She had the audacity to snap back at me with her eyes glaring.
उसकी इतनी हिम्मत थी कि वह घूरती आँखों से मेरी ओर पलटकर देखने लगी।
You should've taught her better.
तुम्हें उसे बेहतर सिखाना चाहिए था.
It would've been a mistake to let her into this family.
उसे इस परिवार में शामिल करना एक गलती होती ।
I thank our ancestors for watching over us.
मैं हमारे पूर्वजों को हमारा ध्यान रखने के लिए धन्यवाद देता हूं।
Hallelujah.
हेलेलुया.
Anyway, if you have any decency,
खैर, अगर आपमें थोड़ी भी शालीनता है,
don't marry her off until she grows as a person.
जब तक वह एक व्यक्ति के रूप में विकसित न हो जाए, तब तक उसका विवाह न करें ।
Don't try to mess up my son's life again,
मेरे बेटे की जिंदगी को फिर से खराब करने की कोशिश मत करो,
and stay away.
और दूर रहो.
Oh, come on. There's obviously a misunderstanding.
अरे, छोड़ो भी। ज़ाहिर है कोई ग़लतफ़हमी है।
Goodness me.
मेरा भला करें।
Ms. Chun, wait.
सुश्री चुन, रुको।
Please don't do this.
कृपया ऐसा मत करो.
Stop being such a loser.
ऐसे हारना बंद करो.
My goodness!
हे भगवान!
[grunts]
[गुर्राहट]
Unbelievable.
अविश्वसनीय.
[gasps]
[हांफते हुए]
My green onion kimchi!
मेरी हरी प्याज किमची!
I'm sorry.
मुझे माफ़ करें।
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[sighs wearily]
[थका हुआ आह भरते हुए]
Oh, what do I do?
ओह, मैं क्या करूँ?
[tires screech]
[टायरों की चीख़]
Goodness me.
मेरा भला करें।
My goodness.
हे भगवान!
Are you all right?
तुम ठीक हो?
Yes, I'm fine.
हां, मैं ठीक हूं।
No, please leave it there. I'll clean it up.
नहीं, कृपया इसे वहीं छोड़ दीजिए। मैं इसे साफ़ कर दूँगा।
It's fine.
यह ठीक है।
Goodness me, how can I ever thank you?
हे भगवान, मैं आपका धन्यवाद कैसे कर सकता हूँ?
Please, just stop.
कृपया, बस रुकें।
Your hands will stink.
तुम्हारे हाथों से बदबू आएगी.
-Your hands will stink. -Thank you.
-आपके हाथों से बदबू आएगी। -धन्यवाद।
[sighs wearily]
[थका हुआ आह भरते हुए]
Are you Ms. Yoo's mother?
क्या आप सुश्री यू की माँ हैं?
Who are...
कौन है...
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
[exclaims softly]
[धीरे से चिल्लाता है]
[hesitates]
[संकोच करता है]
So, you work with Meri's company?
तो, आप मेरी की कंपनी के साथ काम करते हैं?
That's right.
यह सही है।
Something urgent came up, so she asked for a favor.
कुछ जरूरी काम आ गया, इसलिए उसने एक मदद मांगी।
I'm supposed to drive you to the bus terminal.
मुझे आपको बस टर्मिनल तक ले जाना है।
Anyway, feel free to talk to me casually.
खैर, बेझिझक मुझसे बात करें।
Still, you're a team leader.
फिर भी, आप एक टीम लीडर हैं।
Ms. Yoo is the head of her company.
सुश्री यू अपनी कंपनी की प्रमुख हैं।
Well, you're not wrong.
खैर, आप गलत नहीं हैं।
[chuckling]
[हँसते हुए]
Anyway, has Meri been doing a good job?
खैर, क्या मेरी अच्छा काम कर रही है?
Of course.
बिल्कुल।
She's so vital to this project that I came here instead of her.
वह इस परियोजना के लिए इतनी महत्वपूर्ण है कि मैं उसके बजाय यहां आया हूं।
She's giving an important presentation to the chairwoman.
वह अध्यक्षा को एक महत्वपूर्ण प्रस्तुति दे रही हैं।
Goodness.
अच्छाई.
She gives one mean presentation.
वह एक घटिया प्रस्तुति देती है।
You know,
आपको पता है,
even as a little girl, she was bold and outspoken.
छोटी लड़की होने के बावजूद वह साहसी और मुखर थी।
Her drawings were so good that she won an award from the governor.
उसके चित्र इतने अच्छे थे कि उसे राज्यपाल से पुरस्कार मिला।
In school, she always led the art projects. [chuckles]
स्कूल में, वह हमेशा कला परियोजनाओं का नेतृत्व करती थी। [हंसी]
You must've been proud of her.
तुम्हें उस पर गर्व होना चाहिए।
Of course, I was.
बेशक, मैं था.
Well...
कुंआ...
I don't know if you heard them earlier,
मुझे नहीं पता कि आपने उन्हें पहले सुना है या नहीं,
but Meri's not as prickly as she comes across.
लेकिन मेरी उतनी भी कठोर नहीं है जितनी वह दिखती है।
She's as feminine as it gets.
वह अत्यंत स्त्रियोचित है।
She gives everything she has to the people she adores.
वह अपना सबकुछ उन लोगों को दे देती है जिन्हें वह प्यार करती है।
[smacks lips]
[होंठों पर थप्पड़ मारता है]
After her father passed,
उसके पिता के निधन के बाद,
she had to step up as the man of the house.
उसे घर के मुखिया के रूप में आगे आना पड़ा ।
Supporting herself through college and living away from home
कॉलेज की पढ़ाई के दौरान खुद का खर्च उठाना और घर से दूर रहना
made her tougher,
उसे और कठोर बना दिया,
and I'm worried people might misunderstand her.
और मुझे चिंता है कि लोग उसे गलत समझ सकते हैं।
That's not the case.
मामला ऐसा नहीं है.
Everyone likes Ms. Yoo.
हर कोई सुश्री यू को पसंद करता है।
She's cheerful and skilled at her job.
वह खुशमिजाज है और अपने काम में कुशल है।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
She's naturally cheerful and hardworking.
वह स्वाभाविक रूप से खुशमिजाज और मेहनती है।
Do you want to know what happened when she was a kid?
क्या आप जानना चाहते हैं कि जब वह बच्ची थी तो उसके साथ क्या हुआ था?
Goodness me. I'm blabbering to a stranger.
हे भगवान! मैं एक अजनबी से बकवास कर रहा हूँ।
-[both chuckle] -Oh, dear.
-[दोनों हंसते हैं] -ओह, प्रिय।
Can I continue?
क्या मैं जारी रख सकता हूं?
Of course.
बिल्कुल।
She was little at the time, not even 100cm tall.
उस समय वह बहुत छोटी थी, उसकी लंबाई 100 सेमी भी नहीं थी।
She was 99cm.
वह 99 सेमी. की थी।
And I was in bed aching all over with the flu.
और मैं बिस्तर पर पड़ा था और फ्लू से मेरा पूरा शरीर दर्द कर रहा था।
Her dad had just started out as a taxi driver and...
उसके पिता ने टैक्सी ड्राइवर के रूप में काम शुरू किया था और...
-Can you wrap things up? -You should hurry out.
-क्या तुम काम ख़त्म कर सकते हो? -तुम्हें जल्दी से बाहर निकल जाना चाहिए।
[line ringing]
[लाइन रिंगिंग]
Goodness.
अच्छाई.
Why would you come here when I'm leaving soon?
जब मैं जल्द ही जा रहा हूं तो तुम यहां क्यों आए हो ?
[exclaims quizzically]
[आश्चर्यजनक ढंग से कहता है]
At Wooju's place?
वूजू के स्थान पर?
I wasn't able to meet his mother.
मैं उसकी माँ से नहीं मिल सका।
She wasn't home.
वह घर पर नहीं थी.
Whatever.
जो कुछ भी।
I couldn't get in touch with her, so I left.
मैं उससे संपर्क नहीं कर सका, इसलिए मैं वहां से चला गया।
You shouldn't have dropped by unannounced.
तुम्हें बिना बताए यहां नहीं आना चाहिए था।
Call ahead next time.
अगली बार पहले फोन करें.
I got it.
मैं समझ गया।
Who? The team leader?
कौन? टीम लीडर?
Goodness.
अच्छाई.
He's the one who drove me to the bus terminal.
वह वही है जिसने मुझे बस टर्मिनल तक पहुंचाया।
Make sure to thank him.
उसे धन्यवाद अवश्य दें।
Sure, go about your day.
ज़रूर, अपना दिनचर्या जारी रखो।
-[line disconnects] -You can get on the bus.
-[लाइन कट जाती है] -आप बस में चढ़ सकते हैं।
I could've gotten the ticket myself, and now I feel bad.
मैं स्वयं टिकट प्राप्त कर सकता था, और अब मुझे बुरा लग रहा है।
Don't be. Ms. Yoo asked me to.
चिंता मत करो। सुश्री यू ने मुझे ऐसा करने को कहा है।
[chuckles] Sure.
[हंसते हुए] ज़रूर.
By the way...
वैसे...
Don't tell Meri about what happened today.
आज जो हुआ उसके बारे में मेरी को मत बताना।
I'm sure she didn't tell me for a reason.
मुझे यकीन है कि उसने मुझे किसी कारण से नहीं बताया।
What's done is done, so why push her for answers?
जो हो गया सो हो गया, तो फिर उससे जवाब मांगने पर क्यों दबाव डाला जाए?
She's probably feeling even worse.
वह शायद और भी बुरा महसूस कर रही होगी।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
[station announcer] The bus for Yeosu will soon depart.
[स्टेशन उद्घोषक] येओसु के लिए बस जल्द ही रवाना होगी।
-Please board. -I should get going.
-कृपया बस में चढ़ें। -मुझे चलना चाहिए।
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
Visit Yeosu sometime.
कभी येओसु की यात्रा करें।
I'll treat you to a tasty meal.
मैं तुम्हें स्वादिष्ट भोजन खिलाऊँगा।
-Sure. -All right.
-ज़रूर. -ठीक है.
Get going.
जाने देना।
[♪ slow, pleasant music playing]
[♪ धीमा, सुखद संगीत बज रहा है]
Get going already.
अभी से शुरू हो जाओ.
[Kim Wooju] Your mother just left.
[किम वूजू] आपकी माँ अभी-अभी चली गईं।
I stayed until her bus pulled away.
मैं तब तक वहीं रुका रहा जब तक उसकी बस नहीं चली गई।
I'm on my way to your place right now.
मैं अभी आपके घर जा रहा हूँ।
Your mother asked me to drop off a few things.
तुम्हारी माँ ने मुझे कुछ सामान छोड़ने के लिए कहा।
I'll wait for you at home, then.
तो फिर मैं घर पर तुम्हारा इंतज़ार करूंगा.
Sure.
ज़रूर।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
[phone vibrating]
[फ़ोन कंपन]
WOOJU'S SISTER
वूजू की बहन
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
Hello?
नमस्ते?
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[doorbell rings]
[दरवाजे की घंटी बजती है]
[Wooju sighs]
[वूजू आह भरता है]
-Here. -Oh, thanks.
-यहाँ. -ओह, धन्यवाद.
They should go straight into the fridge.
इन्हें सीधे फ्रिज में रख देना चाहिए।
Right.
सही।
Is something up?
क्या कुछ हुआ है?
Gosh, no. [sniffles]
अरे नहीं। [सूँघता है]
The tension's finally leaving now that the presentation's done.
अब जब प्रस्तुतिकरण समाप्त हो गया है तो तनाव अंततः समाप्त हो रहा है ।
Thank you for today.
आज के लिए तुम्हारा धन्यवाद।
I was able to finish it well, thanks to you.
मैं इसे अच्छी तरह से समाप्त करने में सक्षम था, आपका धन्यवाद।
[chuckles] So I heard.
[हंसते हुए] तो मैंने सुना.
Are you sure you're okay?
क्या आप निश्चित हैं कि आप ठीक हैं?
You don't seem well.
आप ठीक नहीं लग रहे हैं.
[sniffles]
[सूँघता है]
Sorry about this. [chuckles softly]
इसके लिए क्षमा करें. [हल्के से हँसते हुए]
I'll take that.
मैं ले जाऊँगा।
My mom...
मेरी माँ...
found out.
पता किया।
WOOJU'S SISTER
वूजू की बहन
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
-Hello? -[angrily] You!
-हैलो? -[गुस्से से] आप!
How could you not have told your mom yet?
तुमने अपनी माँ को अब तक क्यों नहीं बताया?
You've got a lot of nerve.
तुममें बहुत हिम्मत है.
Your mom came by our house!
तुम्हारी माँ हमारे घर आई थी!
My mom had to rest after the shock your mom caused!
आपकी माँ द्वारा दिए गए सदमे के बाद मेरी माँ को आराम करना पड़ा !
I'm dying.
मैं मर रहा हूं।
This is killing me.
यह मुझे मार रहा है.
[sighs] This is exactly why I didn't tell her.
[आह भरते हुए] यही कारण है कि मैंने उसे नहीं बताया।
[sniffles]
[सूँघता है]
I was fine with it all,
मैं इस सब से ठीक था,
but I knew my mom...
लेकिन मैं अपनी माँ को जानता था...
[sniffles] I knew my mom would be upset.
[सूँघता है] मुझे पता था कि मेरी माँ परेशान होगी।
[sniffles]
[सूँघता है]
I should've been there.
मुझे वहां होना चाहिए था.
If I were there, it would've been a fair fight.
अगर मैं वहां होता तो यह एक निष्पक्ष लड़ाई होती।
I bet my mom couldn't even get a word in.
मुझे यकीन है कि मेरी माँ एक शब्द भी नहीं बोल पाएगी।
Then, why don't you bring it up with her?
तो फिर, आप यह बात उसके सामने क्यों नहीं लाते?
She'll soon find out anyway.
वैसे भी उसे जल्द ही पता चल जाएगा।
What can I say, considering what happened?
जो कुछ हुआ उसे देखते हुए मैं क्या कह सकता हूं?
[sighs wearily]
[थका हुआ आह भरते हुए]
I became a divorcée without ever having a wedding.
मैं बिना शादी किये ही तलाकशुदा हो गयी ।
She won't be proud of me anymore.
अब उसे मुझ पर गर्व नहीं होगा.
Come on.
चलो भी।
Why do you always have to be her pride and joy?
आपको हमेशा उसका गौरव और आनंद क्यों बनना पड़ता है ?
What more do you have to be besides her daughter?
उसकी बेटी के अलावा आपके पास और क्या है ?
Don't worry about it too much.
इसके बारे में ज्यादा चिंता मत करो.
Besides, I think she's ready to hear your side of the story.
इसके अलावा, मुझे लगता है कि वह आपकी बात सुनने के लिए तैयार है।
MOM
माँ
[line ringing]
[लाइन रिंगिंग]
[inhales sharply]
[तेजी से साँस लेता है]
[phone ringing]
[फ़ोन बज रहा है]
MERI
उपाय
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
Mom.
माँ।
I have...
मेरे पास है...
-something to tell you. -Meri.
-तुम्हें कुछ बताना है. -मेरी.
Just forget about it all.
बस यह सब भूल जाओ.
He's not the only man out there.
वह वहां अकेला आदमी नहीं है।
I only approved because you liked him.
मैंने केवल इसलिए स्वीकृति दी क्योंकि तुम्हें वह पसंद था।
To be honest,
ईमानदार रहना,
I was never fond of that punk.
मुझे वह गुंडा कभी पसंद नहीं था।
[smacks lips]
[होंठों पर थप्पड़ मारता है]
They say you need to clear out the junk to make room for something better,
वे कहते हैं कि आपको कुछ बेहतर के लिए जगह बनाने के लिए कबाड़ को साफ करना होगा ,
so forget about him and live your life.
इसलिए उसे भूल जाओ और अपना जीवन जियो।
Mom.
माँ।
I'm sorry.
मुझे माफ़ करें।
What are you apologizing for?
आप किस बात के लिए माफ़ी मांग रहे हैं?
Do better and show him what he's missing.
बेहतर काम करें और उसे दिखाएं कि उसमें क्या कमी है।
You already have a place to live,
आपके पास रहने के लिए पहले से ही एक जगह है,
so move on if someone better comes your way.
इसलिए यदि कोई बेहतर व्यक्ति आपके रास्ते में आता है तो आगे बढ़ें ।
[exclaims quizzically]
[आश्चर्यजनक ढंग से कहता है]
You moved?
आप चले गए?
To where?
जहां?
[breath trembling]
[सांस कांपना]
You won a prize?
आपने कोई पुरस्कार जीता?
[stutters] What...
[हकलाते हुए] क्या...
What exactly did you win?
आपने वास्तव में क्या जीता?
Wooju doesn't know.
वूजू को नहीं पता.
Of course, I tried calling him.
बेशक, मैंने उसे फोन करने की कोशिश की।
I tried over and over.
मैंने बार-बार कोशिश की.
What can I do when he won't pick up?
जब वह फोन नहीं उठाएगा तो मैं क्या कर सकता हूं?
All right.
ठीक है।
Meri, listen to me loud and clear.
मेरी, मेरी बात ज़ोर से और साफ़ सुनो।
You...
आप...
No matter what, don't get caught.
चाहे कुछ भी हो जाए, पकड़े मत जाना।
-[♪ dramatic music playing] -[exclaims quizzically]
-[♪ नाटकीय संगीत बज रहा है] -[आश्चर्यजनक ढंग से कहता है]
Are you sure I should keep this up?
क्या आप निश्चित हैं कि मुझे यह जारी रखना चाहिए?
What if I get caught?
अगर मैं पकड़ा गया तो क्या होगा?
You should make sure no one finds out.
आपको यह सुनिश्चित करना चाहिए कि किसी को पता न चले।
Always watch what you say.
हमेशा ध्यान रखें कि आप क्या कहते हैं।
Meri,
उपाय,
stay strong.
हिम्मत बनायें रखें।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
Got it.
समझ गया।
Don't worry.
चिंता मत करो।
Right.
सही।
Sure.
ज़रूर।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[sighs]
[आह भरते हुए]
What the heck?
क्या बिल्ली है?
Who knew Mom was so cool?
कौन जानता था कि माँ इतनी अच्छी थी?
The world isn't as harsh as you might imagine.
दुनिया उतनी कठोर नहीं है जितनी आप सोचते हैं।
You?
आप?
You threw your own happiness away.
तुमने अपनी खुशियाँ ही खो दीं।
[♪ gripping comical music playing]
[♪ मनोरंजक हास्य संगीत बज रहा है]
That's karma at work.
यह कर्म का काम है।
My gosh.
अरे बाप रे।
You know what this is?
तुम जानते हो यह क्या है?
It's amor fati.
यह अमोर फ़ाति है।
[firework whistles]
[आतिशबाज़ी की सीटियाँ]
[singing] ♪ Amor fati ♪
[गायन] ♪ Amor fati ♪
[sings happily]
[खुशी से गाता है]
-♪ Amor fati ♪ -[Meri] But sometimes,
-♪ अमोर फाति ♪ -[मेरी] लेकिन कभी-कभी,
the least expected also happens.
सबसे कम अपेक्षित घटना भी घटित होती है।
[♪ jazz music playing over speakers]
[♪ स्पीकर पर जैज़ संगीत बज रहा है]
I've never had meat this tender before.
मैंने पहले कभी इतना कोमल मांस नहीं खाया था।
[giggles]
[हंसी]
Baby, have some.
बेबी, कुछ खा लो।
Thanks.
धन्यवाद।
-Dig in, too. -Sure.
-तुम भी खोदो। -ज़रूर।
[phone vibrating]
[फ़ोन कंपन]
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
Baby, what's after dinner?
बेबी, रात के खाने के बाद क्या है?
Why do you ask?
तुम क्यों पूछ रहे हो?
A friend's in the neighborhood, so I thought we'd meet up.
पड़ोस में मेरा एक दोस्त रहता है, इसलिए मैंने सोचा कि हम मिल लें।
A friend? Who?
एक दोस्त? कौन?
A school friend who lives close by.
एक स्कूल मित्र जो पास में ही रहता है।
I'll make introductions later.
मैं बाद में परिचय दूंगा.
-Sure, got it. -Hmm.
-ज़रूर, समझ गया। -हम्म।
[clears throat]
[गला साफ़ करता है]
Sure thing.
अवश्य।
[elevator dings]
[लिफ्ट की आवाज़]
-See you later.
-बाद में मिलते हैं।
[whispers] I love you.
[फुसफुसाते हुए] मैं तुमसे प्यार करता हूँ.
[whispers] I love you, too.
[फुसफुसाते हुए] मैं भी तुमसे प्यार करता हूँ।
-Don't be gone for too long. -Got it.
-ज्यादा देर तक मत जाओ। -समझ गया।
[♪ tense foreboding music playing]
[♪ तनावपूर्ण अशुभ संगीत बज रहा है]
Damn it.
धत तेरी कि।
Hurry!
जल्दी करो!
[elevator dings]
[लिफ्ट की आवाज़]
[woman screams]
[महिला चीखती है]
[exclaims]
[चिल्लाता है]
[elevator dings]
[लिफ्ट की आवाज़]
See you soon.
जल्द ही फिर मिलेंगे।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[panting]
[हाँफते हुए]
[exclaims softly]
[धीरे से चिल्लाता है]
Which floor?
कौनसी मंजिल?
[breathing heavily]
[भारी साँस लेते हुए]
Shit.
छीः.
1 UNREAD MESSAGE
1 अपठित संदेश
C: I'M IN ROOM 3613
सी: मैं कमरा 3613 में हूँ
Room 3613.
कमरा 3613.
Why won't it work?
यह काम क्यों नहीं करेगा?
The hotel key card.
होटल कुंजी कार्ड.
Come on. [breath trembling]
चलो. [कांपती हुई सांस]
Why won't it work?
यह काम क्यों नहीं करेगा?
Come on.
चलो भी।
Damn it!
धत तेरी कि!
[elevator dings]
[लिफ्ट की आवाज़]
[♪ dramatic sting]
[♪ नाटकीय स्टिंग]
[exclaims]
[चिल्लाता है]
[♪ foreboding music playing]
[♪ अशुभ संगीत बज रहा है]
[in English] Sorry.
[अंग्रेज़ी में] क्षमा करें.
[in Korean] Shit.
[कोरियाई में] बकवास.
Shit.
छीः.
[panting]
[हाँफते हुए]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[♪ रोमांचक संगीत बज रहा है]
Jenny?
जेनी?
Jenny...
जेनी...
[continues panting]
[हाँफना जारी रखता है]
[doorbell chiming]
[दरवाजे की घंटी बजती है]
-Baby. -Babe.
-बेबी बेब।
[♪ dramatic guitar music playing]
[♪ नाटकीय गिटार संगीत बजाना]
Wow, she made so much food.
वाह, उसने बहुत सारा खाना बनाया।
Always so generous, isn't she?
वह हमेशा इतनी उदार रहती है, है न?
[hums softly]
[धीरे से गुनगुनाता है]
[exclaims] It's so good.
[कहते हैं] यह बहुत अच्छा है.
MOM
माँ
Hey, Mom. What's up?
अरे माँ, क्या हाल है?
Unbelievable.
अविश्वसनीय.
I've looked everywhere.
मैंने हर जगह देखा है.
It isn't in any of my pockets.
यह मेरी किसी भी जेब में नहीं है।
No way. I didn't even pull my wallet out on the bus.
बिल्कुल नहीं। मैंने बस में अपना बटुआ भी नहीं निकाला ।
Goodness.
अच्छाई.
You know what?
तुम्हें पता है क्या?
I must have dropped it there.
मैंने इसे वहां गिरा दिया होगा।
In Mr. Kim's car?
श्री किम की कार में?
Sure, I'll ask.
ज़रूर, मैं पूछूंगा.
Got it.
समझ गया।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
TEAM LEADER KIM WOOJU
टीम लीडर किम वूजू
[line ringing]
[लाइन रिंगिंग]
A black folding wallet?
एक काला फोल्डिंग बटुआ?
I'll look for it.
मैं इसकी तलाश करूंगा.
Sure.
ज़रूर।
[line disconnects]
[लाइन डिस्कनेक्ट]
[grunts]
[गुर्राहट]
Why did I miss this?
मैं यह क्यों भूल गया?
OH YOUNGSOOK
ओह यंगसूक
-[♪ enchanting music playing] -Sometimes, the thing you're searching for
-[♪ मनमोहक संगीत बज रहा है] -कभी-कभी, वह चीज़ जिसे आप खोज रहे होते हैं
is right under your nose.
आपकी नाक के ठीक नीचे है।
Seriously?
गंभीरता से?
YOUNGSOOK'S RESTAURANT
यंगसूक रेस्टोरेंट
[♪ poignant, melancholy music playing]
[♪ मार्मिक, उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[teddy] Enough with the tears, or the tiger will come and get you.
[टेडी] बहुत हो गया आँसू, वरना बाघ आएगा और तुम्हें ले जाएगा।
Take it.
इसे लें।
My dad gave it to me as a birthday gift.
मेरे पिताजी ने इसे मुझे जन्मदिन के उपहार के रूप में दिया था।
The girl I'd been looking for
वह लड़की जिसकी मुझे तलाश थी
was right under my nose.
मेरी नाक के ठीक नीचे था।
[chuckles softly]
[हल्के से हँसता है]
I wonder if she knew.
मुझे आश्चर्य है कि क्या वह जानती थी?
[♪ poignant, melancholy music continues]
[♪ मार्मिक, उदासी भरा संगीत जारी है]
[tires screech, car horn blaring]
[टायरों की चीख़, कार का हॉर्न बजना]
[truck horn blaring]
[ट्रक का हॉर्न बज रहा है]
[car horn continues blaring]
[कार का हॉर्न बजता रहता है]
[tires screeching]
[टायरों की चीख़]
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[♪ उदासी भरा संगीत बज रहा है]
[student in English] Are you okay?
[छात्र अंग्रेजी में] क्या आप ठीक हैं?
Are you okay?
तुम ठीक हो?
[Kim Wooju] That when harsh winds swept through my lonely heart...
[किम वूजू] जब कठोर हवाएं मेरे एकाकी हृदय से गुज़रीं...
[student] Oh, no.
[छात्र] ओह, नहीं.
...the warmth from a girl I'd just met brought me...
...एक लड़की से मिली गर्मजोशी ने मुझे...
[teddy] Enough with the tears,
[टेडी] बहुत हो गए आँसू,
-[Kim Wooju] ...a brief moment of peace. -or the tiger will come and get you.
-[किम वूजू] ...थोड़े समय की शांति. -वरना बाघ आएगा और तुम्हें ले जाएगा।
[♪ upbeat pop music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक पॉप संगीत बज रहा है]
Who will take care of him?
उसकी देखभाल कौन करेगा?
That poor boy!
वह बेचारा लड़का!
[Kim Wooju] She cried for me.
[किम वूजू] वह मेरे लिए रोई।
Could you perhaps stop by just this once?
क्या आप शायद एक बार यहां रुक सकते हैं?
MUTE
आवाज़ बंद करना
[laughing softly]
[धीरे से हँसते हुए]
When I met her again,
जब मैं उससे दोबारा मिला,
I wanted to say
मैं कहना चाहता था
[clears throat]
[गला साफ़ करता है]
how grateful I was.
मैं कितना आभारी था.
Hold on.
पकड़ना।
What are you doing this weekend?
आप इस सप्ताहांत पर क्या कर रहे हैं?
Shouldn't you have a wedding photo or something?
क्या आपके पास शादी की फोटो या कुछ और नहीं होना चाहिए?
That'd lower his suspicion.
इससे उसका संदेह कम हो जाएगा।
He was clearly suspicious last time.
पिछली बार वह स्पष्ट रूप से संदिग्ध था।
With you gone...
तुम्हारे चले जाने के बाद...
He's watching us.
वह हमें देख रहा है.
-He really is. -[chuckles softly]
-वह सचमुच है। -[हल्के से हँसता है]
Everyone likes Ms. Yoo.
हर कोई सुश्री यू को पसंद करता है।
She's cheerful and skilled at her job.
वह खुशमिजाज है और अपने काम में कुशल है।
[chuckles]
[हंसी]
She's naturally cheerful and hardworking.
वह स्वाभाविक रूप से खुशमिजाज और मेहनती है।
Do you want to know...
क्या आप जानना चाहते हैं...
[Kim Wooju] But I never asked
[किम वूजू] लेकिन मैंने कभी नहीं पूछा
if she remembered me.
अगर वह मुझे याद करती.
This was enough distance.
यह दूरी पर्याप्त थी।
I was repaying the favor
मैं एहसान चुका रहा था
by helping her this much.
उसकी इतनी मदद करके.
[♪ pleasant, upbeat music playing]
[♪ सुखद, उत्साहवर्धक संगीत बज रहा है]
[phone vibrating]
[फ़ोन कंपन]
Hey, did you find it?
अरे, क्या तुम्हें यह मिल गया?
[Wooju] It's me.
[वूजू] यह मैं हूं।
How have you been?
क्या आप?
[♪ upbeat pop music playing]
[♪ उत्साहवर्धक पॉप संगीत बज रहा है]
WOULD YOU MARRY ME?
क्या तुम मुझसे शादी करोगे?
[Meri] I'm supposed to work with Managing Director Baek?
[मेरी] क्या मुझे प्रबंध निदेशक बेक के साथ काम करना चाहिए?
[Kim Wooju] Call me three times a day, no exceptions.
[किम वूजू] मुझे दिन में तीन बार फोन करें, कोई अपवाद नहीं।
[Wooju] I'm choosing you, Meri.
[वूजू] मैं तुम्हें चुन रहा हूँ, मेरी।
[Jingyeong] Who could possibly save you, Wooju?
[जिंगयेओंग] वूजू, तुम्हें कौन बचा सकता है ?
There's no need to look very far.
बहुत दूर तक देखने की कोई जरूरत नहीं है।
[Eungsoo's mom] He's lucky he wasn't kicked out of the family.
[युंगसू की माँ] वह भाग्यशाली है कि उसे परिवार से बाहर नहीं निकाला गया।
[Kim Wooju] My parents passed away on my birthday,
[किम वूजू] मेरे माता-पिता का निधन मेरे जन्मदिन पर हुआ,
and it was my fault.
और यह मेरी गलती थी.
[Wooju] The house is that punk's, isn't it?
[वूजू] घर तो उस गुंडे का है, है न?
[Meri] Didn't you say to team up with Wooju if push came to shove?
[मेरी] क्या आपने यह नहीं कहा था कि अगर जरूरत पड़ी तो वूजू के साथ मिलकर काम करना होगा?
[Kim Wooju] Maybe it's because I like you.
[किम वूजू] शायद ऐसा इसलिए है क्योंकि मैं तुम्हें पसंद करता हूँ।
I don't like seeing you with another guy.
मुझे तुम्हें किसी दूसरे लड़के के साथ देखना पसंद नहीं है।
Does it bother you that I like you?
क्या तुम्हें इस बात से परेशानी है कि मैं तुम्हें पसंद करता हूँ?
[♪ ethereal sparkle]
[♪ अलौकिक चमक]
Translated by Hyelim Park
हाइलिम पार्क द्वारा अनुवादित